Thank you.
谢谢。
¶¶
¶¶
All right.
好的。
Welcome back to the Ethereum Protocol Fellowship Study Group.
欢迎回到以太坊协议研究小组。
We are here in our final week, week 10, on the development track.
我们在第10周的最后一周，在开发轨道上。
It's been a good couple of months here learning all about Ethereum and diving into different topics here.
这里已经有一个好几个月了，在这里学习了有关以太坊的所有知识，并在这里研究了不同的主题。
Today on our final development track talk, we'll be speaking with Dano from Basu,
今天，在我们的最终发展轨道谈话中，我们将与巴苏（Basu）的达诺（Dano）交谈
and he'll be talking about precompile.
他将谈论预编译。
So I'll go ahead and pass it off to Mario.
因此，我将继续将其传递给Mario。
You can give Dano a little bit more of a proper introduction,
您可以给Dano提供更多适当的介绍，
and then you can take it away, Dano.
然后，您可以将其带走，Dano。
Hello, everyone. Welcome here, Dano.
大家好。欢迎在这里，达诺。
Thank you so much for joining us today.
非常感谢您今天加入我们。
And yeah, it's our very last week,
是的，这是我们上周，
our last talk on the development track,
我们在开发轨道上的最后一个谈话，
and we have a very special guest for this
我们有一个非常特别的嘉宾
because Dano has been a developer for, well, decades now.
因为达诺已经成为数十年的开发人员。
He's really one of the OG Java developers in the Ethereum ecosystem.
他实际上是以太坊生态系统中的OG Java开发人员之一。
and while I've been doing my little research,
当我从事小研究时
I found out that he's been working,
我发现他一直在工作，
he had a whole career before starting Ethereum,
在开始以太坊之前，他有整个职业
working in Google, in Oracle,
在Google，Oracle工作，
and even publishing a book on front-end in Java,
甚至出版有关Java前端的书，
if I'm correct, right?
如果我正确，对吗？
Yeah, you did your research.
是的，您进行了研究。
Yeah, I wanted to tell you about you.
是的，我想告诉你你。
And yes, it's been a project since 2013
是的，这是自2013年以来的一个项目
and then during Ethereum in 2018,
然后在2018年以太坊期间
which doesn't seem that long ago,
似乎不久前
but it's been like six years of working in the core Ethereum
但这就像在核心以太坊工作六年
on the Hyperledger client,
在HyperLeDger客户端，
Bessu client, which is the Java implementation.
Bessu客户端，这是Java实施。
So, and today it's focused in this specialty,
因此，今天它专注于这个专业，
pre-compiles their integration clients
预编译其集成客户
and how the clients use them.
以及客户如何使用它们。
Yeah, very excited.
是的，非常兴奋。
Thank you so much again for being here.
非常感谢您在这里。
And yeah, the stage is yours.
是的，舞台是你的。
feel free to share the screen and go ahead and start.
随时分享屏幕并继续开始。
So yeah, we're here to talk about pre-images. Just kidding,
是的，我们在这里谈论前图像。只是在开玩笑，
we're here to talk about pre-compiles. But it's interesting, Mario brought up
我们在这里谈论预编译。但这很有趣，马里奥长大了
that I had a full career before I got involved in Ethereum. It was some of that that actually
在我参与以太坊之前，我有一个完整的职业。实际上是
brought me into blockchain. I used to be a Java desktop front-end UI developer back before the web
把我带入了区块链。我曾经是Java台式机前端UI开发人员，然后再回到网络
completely dominated everything. At one point, the Swing UI library was the top-used library
完全统治着一切。在某一时刻，Swing UI库是最受欢迎的库
and enterprises. So one of the things that was being added late in the life of the Java desktop
和企业。因此，Java桌面生命后期正在添加的一件事
was this toolkit called JavaFX. And they had this new revolutionary layout engine called a,
这个工具包称为javafx。他们拥有这个新的革命性布局引擎，称为A
well it's not revolutionary to a lot of people, but to Java it was, called a scene graph where
好吧，这对很多人来说不是革命性的，而是爪哇，它被称为场景图
you can just put components here and draw lines between them. You don't have to put stuff into
您可以将组件放在这里并在它们之间划清界限。你不必把东西放入
a grid and match anything up. You can just draw graphs. So I found a graph layout library because
网格并匹配任何东西。您可以绘制图形。所以我找到了一个图布局库，因为
my job used graph layouts. And I wanted to put it in JavaFX. And I wanted to play with this,
我的工作使用图形布局。我想把它放在Javafx中。我想和这个
these fancy graph layouts. And I really needed some interesting data to get interesting real
这些精美的图形布局。我真的需要一些有趣的数据才能变得有趣
world graphs from. And this is about the time Bitcoin had just hit its first thousand dollar
来自世界图。这是比特币刚刚达到了第一千美元的时间
peak. And so I've been reading up on Bitcoin and the UTXOs are just very natural,
顶峰。因此，我一直在阅读比特币，UTXOS非常自然，
acyclic directed graphs with really interesting data on it. So I had this ready and I got really
无环向图具有非常有趣的数据。所以我已经准备好了，我真的得到了
lucky I happened to stumble across the Mt. Gox doing its big pyramid split during its bankruptcy,
幸运的是，我碰巧偶然发现了戈克斯山在破产期间进行大金字塔裂口，
did some YouTube videos, and that just took me right down to the deep rabbit hole
做了一些YouTube视频，这只是让我直接到达深兔子洞
of doing blockchain. And I switched over to doing Ethereum full-time. I spent three years at Google
做区块链。我转身全职做以太坊。我在Google呆了三年
thinking it's a nice place. I can get blockchain out of my head. Didn't work. Didn't work one bit.
认为这是一个好地方。我可以从脑海中脱颖而出。不起作用。一点点工作。
So when ConsenSys called me and asked me, hey, do you want to work on a Java Ethereum client? I was
因此，当共识打电话给我并问我时，嘿，您想在Java以太坊客户端工作吗？我是
like, oh yes, I absolutely do. So that's, you know, that's how you get in, just little things
就像，哦，是的，我绝对做。这就是你知道的，那就是你的进来，只是小事
get you interested. And there are so many nerd snipes in Ethereum that's just crazy. So many
让您有兴趣。以太坊中有很多书呆子狙击真是太疯狂了。这么多
things that are being applied and so many techniques that can be used from older systems.
正在应用的东西以及可以从较旧系统中使用的许多技术。
So today, what I'm going to be talking about is pre-compiles. And that probably,
所以今天，我要谈论的是预编译。那可能，
to a lot of people, sounds like an incredibly boring subject. You know, we're going to talk
对于很多人来说，听起来像是一个令人难以置信的主题。你知道，我们要谈谈
about how you execute, you know, hash functions and all that other stuff. And that's not actually
关于您的执行方式，您知道，哈希功能和所有其他内容。实际上不是
what I'm going to talk much about. I'm going to talk about how pre-compiles, I view them
我要谈的是很多。我要谈论预编译的方式，我会看到它们
as EVM's escape hatch to do interesting things outside
当EVM的逃生舱口在外面做有趣的事情
of the EVM, and yet still keep things deterministic and provable within
EVM的范围，但仍保持确定性和可证明的事物
a blockchain context. And we're going to look at how Mainnet does it, and we're going to look
区块链上下文。我们将研究主网的方式，我们将看
at some of the ways how Layer 2s do it, and how
第2层如何做到的某些方式以及如何
Layer 1s use it to interact with their systems. And I didn't have time to write
第1层使用它与他们的系统进行交互。而且我没有时间写
up slides for this, but there's a really rich area on how pre-compiles are going to be used
为此幻灯片，但是在如何使用预编译方面有一个非常丰富的领域
for more exotic things like fully homomorphic encryption
对于更多的异国情调，例如完全同态加密
and AI large language model integrations.
和AI大语言模型集成。
So let me get to my screen.
因此，让我进入屏幕。
So here's a brief agenda.
因此，这是一个简短的议程。
Like I said, this is not a cryptography presentation.
就像我说的那样，这不是密码介绍。
I am not a cryptographer.
我不是一个密码学家。
I know what these cryptographic algorithms do.
我知道这些加密算法是什么。
I know as a developer how I would use them,
我知道作为开发人员如何使用它们，
but I have no idea how Galois field is generated
但是我不知道如何生成加洛伊斯领域
and how to prove that ZK systems
以及如何证明ZK系统
actually do what they claim to do.
实际做他们声称要做的事情。
But I know how to use them. And that's really as a developer in Ethereum and any cryptocurrency in any crypto spaces, it's going to be almost impossible to know literally how literally everything works.
但是我知道如何使用它们。这实际上是作为以太坊的开发人员和任何加密空间中的任何加密货币，几乎不可能知道从字面上知道一切的工作方式。
But what you really need to know is what it does, why it does it, and who the experts are to talk to if you're going to try to do something exotic.
但是，您真正需要知道的是它的作用，为什么要做，以及如果您要尝试做一些异国情调的专家，那么专家将与谁交谈。
So we're going to talk first about what pre-compiles are and the main examples.
因此，我们将首先讨论哪些预编译和主要示例。
tables. We're going to dive into how they work. Then we're going to talk about use outside
表。我们将深入研究它们的工作方式。那我们要谈论外面的使用
of Ethereum main net. Finally, I'm going to wrap up with a few future developments of
以太坊主要网。最后，我将总结一下未来的发展
what's actually coming in main net and L2s. So, we'll go there.
实际网和L2S中实际上是什么。所以，我们会去那里。
So, when I talk about precompiles, though, I'm really talking about three different kinds
因此，当我谈论预编译时，我真的在谈论三种不同的类型
of contracts. Precompiles are what started the whole precompile thing. There are tasks
合同。预编译是启动整个预编译的原因。有任务
you could do in EVM, but they're too expensive and too slow to do in EVM. Massive amounts
您可以在EVM中执行，但是它们太昂贵且太慢，无法在EVM中进行。大量
of bit twiddling, like the Kachak hash that requires a lot of bit twiddling. You could do
有点摇摇欲坠，就像Kachak Hash需要大量twiddling一样。你可以做
that in the EVM. It's going to cost you, I don't know, millions of gas to do. And there are much
在EVM中。我不知道，这将使您花费数百万美元。而且有很多
more efficient and much more optimized implementations of Kachak that use fancy compiler,
使用精美编译器的Kachak更有效，更优化的实现，
fancy processor instructions like SSE and whatever the current iteration of SSE is on the Intel chips
诸如SSE之类的花式处理器指令以及SSE当前的Intel芯片上的任何迭代
and whatever the equivalents on the ARM chips are. They can do Kachak hashing just really,
无论手臂芯片上的等效物是什么。他们真的可以做Kachak哈希，
really fast. So that's why they exist. So we can take stuff that has a well-known input A,
真的很快。这就是为什么它们存在。因此，我们可以采用具有众所周知的输入a的东西，
gives input DB, and do it very efficiently and very fast. Now it's interesting I mentioned
给出输入DB，并非常有效，非常快。现在很有趣
Kachak. There is no Kachak precompile. Kachak is the one example of a cryptographic primitive
卡查。没有Kachak预编译。 Kachak是加密原始的一个例子
that has an opcode. It's in a 20 block, the hex 20 block, and it's probably going to be the only
有一个opcode。它位于20个街区，十六进制20街区，这可能是唯一的
thing in the hex 20 block. I foresee all future crypto things coming in through precompiles
十六进制20街区的东西。我预见了所有未来的加密货币。
because they're just generally too expensive for opcodes.
因为它们通常太昂贵，而对于opcodes来说。
The second kind of a precompile is a system contract.
第二种预编译是系统合同。
We don't see this in Ethereum mainnet.
我们在以太坊主网中看不到这一点。
We see this mostly in layer twos,
我们大多在两层中看到了这一点，
and we see this in alt VMs, alt layer ones.
我们在Alt VM的Alt层中看到了这一点。
These are the kinds of system contracts
这些是系统合同的种类
that take something in EVM
在EVM中带了一些东西
and they do something in a different layer
他们在不同的一层做某事
or in a foreign system in the blockchain
或在区块链中的外国系统中
that aren't exactly EVM,
这不是EVM，
and they come back and do stuff.
他们回来做事。
So you wouldn't want to worry about
所以你不想担心
connecting with your disk storage.
连接您的磁盘存储。
You have, you know, you have your regular contract storage, but there's things you might need to store network communications with L2 that you would farm out to the L2 node software to run.
您知道，您有常规的合同存储，但是您可能需要与L2存储网络通信的一些事情，您可以将其耕种到L2节点软件中运行。
And those are done through what I call system contracts because they break layers.
这些是通过我所说的系统合同来完成的，因为它们会破坏层。
And that's what distinguishes a pre-compile from a system contract is that they escape the sandbox and do things the EVM should not do.
这就是将预编译与系统合同区别的区别在于，它们逃脱了沙箱，并做EVM不应该做的事情。
And finally, there's kind of something in between these called pre-deployed contracts.
最后，这些所谓的预部合同之间存在一些东西。
um pre-deployed contracts use techniques to break layers but at the core they're really just um evm
UM前部署的合同使用技术破坏层，但在核心上，它们实际上只是EVM
code that is pre-deployed to genesis or might come in as part of a fork and they're put at specific
预先部署创世纪的代码或可能是叉子的一部分，它们是特定的
addresses and the addresses they exist at um might be you know special in name it's not something you
地址及其存在的地址可能是您知道特殊的，这不是您
could cryptographically deploy to sometimes they are but these pre-deployed contracts they just
有时可以在这些预部计划的合同中部署到密码，而这些合同
show up and they're used and um they come as part of the genesis file or as part of a hard fork and
出现并使用它们，嗯，它们是创世记文件的一部分，或者是硬叉的一部分，
And there's even like a fourth miner case where you just deploy a contract and rely
甚至还有第四个矿工案件，您刚刚部署合同并依靠
on some of these techniques, but we'll get to that later in the presentation.
在其中一些技术上，但我们将在演示文稿中进行稍后进行。
So as of Cancun today, here are the nine pre-compiles that exist on Ethereum mainnet.
因此，与今天的坎昆（Cancun）一样，以太坊主网上存在的九个预编译。
And they exist at the low numbers.
它们的数量很少。
I list these as 0x01.
我将其列为0x01。
Really it's 0x3100s and then 01.
确实是0x3100，然后是01。
So if you call these in the address, there will be a lot of zeros in it.
因此，如果您在地址中调用这些，则其中会有很多零。
And it's kind of convenient when you're doing EVM calls, because you can just push one to
当您进行EVM电话时，这很方便，因为您可以将一个人推到
bring it in, rather than doing a push 20 with a lot of zeros to bring in the address.
带上它，而不是用很多零来进行20次推进来引入地址。
So it makes it fairly efficient to call these.
因此，将其称为相当有效。
So the first four were brought in at Genesis.
因此，前四个被引入了创世纪。
The next one of them was brought in by, four of them are brought in Byzantium.
下一个是由其中的四个带入拜占庭的。
One of them was brought in Istanbul, and one of them was brought in Cancun.
其中一个被带到伊斯坦布尔，其中一名被带到坎昆。
The performance brought into Genesis were really essential to the foundations of Ethereum to make it work.
进入创世纪的表现对于以太坊的基础确实至关重要。
The first one is called EC-RECOVER.
第一个被称为EC Recover。
And what it does is it takes a hash, a commitment, makes a hash commitment out of it if it's too large.
它的作用是，如果它太大，则需要进行哈希的承诺。
No, it just takes a 32-byte commit.
不，它只需要32个字节的提交。
You have to hash it yourself.
你必须自己哈希。
So it takes a message.
因此，它需要一条消息。
It performs the SECP-256-K1 signature recovery on it if it was a signature.
如果它是签名，它在其上执行SECP-256-K1签名恢复。
Yeah, it's just recovery.
是的，这只是恢复。
So you need the commitment, and you need the signature piece.
因此，您需要承诺，并且需要签名作品。
it's a way to take commitments and create Ethereum addresses out of it.
这是一种承诺并创建以太坊地址的方式。
Because it does an extra step, which is it chops off the top 12 bytes,
因为它做出了额外的步骤，这就是从前12个字节上脱落的，所以
it only gives you the lower 20 bytes for an Ethereum address.
它只为您提供以太坊地址的20个字节。
Precompile number two, it's SHA-2-256, it's the precursor to Kachak.
第二次编译是SHA-2-256，它是Kachak的先驱。
And it's a hash, you go over large amounts of data, and you compress it,
这是一个哈希，您会浏览大量数据，然后将其压缩，
and you get the same amount of data.
您会得到相同数量的数据。
data, and you compress it, and you get the hash out of it. So that's one hash algorithm that is
数据，然后将其压缩，然后将其从中获得。所以那是一种哈希算法
used in Ethereum. RIPMD160 is a hash algorithm, not used in Ethereum, but it is used in Bitcoin.
用于以太坊。 RIPMD160是一种哈希算法，不在以太坊中使用，但在比特币中使用。
It's used in Ethereum, and it exists as a pre-compile. But RIPMD is used in some instances
它用于以太坊，并作为预编译存在。但是RIPMD在某些情况下使用
of Bitcoin, and so it's put there in compatibility in case we needed to verify Bitcoin signatures.
比特币，因此，如果我们需要验证比特币特征，则将其置于兼容性。
Not terribly used a lot, although it's not zero. It's one of the least used ones out there.
尽管不是零，但并没有大量使用。这是那里使用最少的人之一。
I think it's the second least used pre-compile on mainnet.
我认为这是Mainnet上第二次最少的预编译。
And the fourth one is identity.
第四个是身份。
This is also one that is ripe for removal because there's more efficient ways to do it.
这也是拆除的成熟，因为有更有效的方法可以做到这一点。
Identity, all it does is it just copies the input to the output.
身份，只需将输入复制到输出。
So it was one way that you could copy memory into different parts of memory.
因此，这是您可以将内存复制到内存的不同部分的一种方式。
We now have mCopyOp code, which does this really efficiently.
现在，我们拥有McOpyop代码，它确实有效地做到了。
So the identity is not truly needed anymore.
因此，不再需要身份。
So as Ethereum grew, I figured out we needed more and more cryptographic primitives.
因此，随着以太坊的成长，我发现我们需要越来越多的加密原语。
05 is mod exp, modular exponentiation. This is a function that I think is used in a lot of
05是mod exp，模块化指数。这是我认为在很多地方使用的功能
RSA signatures, but it's also used as a primitive in a lot of other cryptographic systems. And it
RSA签名，但在许多其他加密系统中也被用作原始签名。然后
does what it does, it does modular exponentiation. You take a number, you take it to a certain
做什么，它可以进行模块化凸起。您取一个数字，将其带到一定
exponent and you take a modulus but these are like really large numbers they're not stuff that you
指数，您采用模量，但这些数字确实很大，它们不是您的东西
would do by hand um we're talking 256-bit 1024-bit solutions um the next three is a group of related
嗯，我们会说256位1024位解决方案um下三个是一组相关的
um pre-compiles um and these are used for um not the standard form of bls it's used but it is a
UM预编译UM，这些用于UM不是使用的标准形式，但它是一个
lesser weaker form of bls can be used for these um these are um addition multiplication and pairing
较小的BLS形式可用于这些UM，这些是UM添加乘法和配对
of a curve it's called alt bn 128 I've heard it's also called bn 254 there's lots of names of it
在曲线中，它叫做Alt Bn 128，我听说它也称为BN 254有很多名称
but it's a it's a 256 version bit version of some of the primitives used in bls and so a lot of
但这是BLS中使用的某些原语的256版本版本，所以很多
people will use this for aggregated signatures and there's some really involved not too involved
人们将使用它进行汇总的签名，并且有些确实涉及不太参与
but there's a processes where you can take the various signatures put them together and you can
但是在某个过程中，您可以将各种签名放在一起，您可以
get one small signature out of it and you can verify that and I'm not really up on a lot of
从中获得一个小签名，您可以验证这一点，我并没有真正完成很多
the math on that. Like I said, not a cryptography talk, but those are the three primitives that you
关于那的数学。就像我说的那样，不是密码学的谈话，而是您的三个原始人
would need to do such BLS in 256 bits. The BLS signatures used in the consensus layer do not
需要在256位进行这样的BLS。共识层中使用的BLS签名不
use this. They use a different curve, BLS 12384 or something, but they are not this. There's a
使用此。他们使用不同的曲线，BLS 12384之类的东西，但不是这个。有一个
proposal to bring them in in Prague, and I think I'll cover it. I may have that on another slide,
提议将它们带入布拉格，我想我会介绍它。我可能会在另一张幻灯片上
but I'll cover it there. So this was in Byzantium. This was back in 2018. The next precompile that
但是我会在那里介绍。所以这是在拜占庭的。这是在2018年。下一个预编译
was added in 2020 was the Blake2bf function, and this is one I think is the least used precompile
在2020年添加的是Blake2bf功能，这是我认为是最少使用的预编译
out there, and the hope was that this would be used for things like zkcache and other zk systems
在那里，希望这将用于ZKCACHE和其他ZK Systems之类的东西
because it used the Blake compression algorithm,
因为它使用了Blake压缩算法，所以
and it was thought that just the F function will be sufficient.
有人认为，仅F功能就足够了。
And this is an example of, I would argue this is a process fail,
这就是一个例子，我认为这是一个过程失败，
but it's hard to say this was a necessary fail for us to learn from it.
但是很难说这是我们从中学习的必要失败。
There was some interest to get it in.
有一定的兴趣进入。
A champion came in and really pushed it forward,
冠军进来，真的将其推向前进，
but there wasn't really any live demand for it,
但是实际上没有任何实时需求
and demand never really developed
需求从未真正发展
because it didn't quite have all of the pieces in there
因为它没有所有的作品
because it wasn't quite ready to verify some of the zcache stuff out there.
因为还没有准备好验证一些Zcache的东西。
So it's unfortunately, if we just did the Blake2 hash algorithm,
因此，不幸的是，如果我们只是做了Blake2哈希算法，
we'd be in a much better place than if we just had the f function.
与刚刚拥有F功能相比，我们的位置要好得多。
But there was reasons why they thought we just needed the f function
但是有原因为什么他们认为我们只需要F功能
and we could compile it together.
我们可以一起编译。
So kind of an unfortunate story.
如此不幸的故事。
And the last one was added just a couple of months ago.
最后一个是几个月前添加的。
I think it's been a couple of months that we've had the cancun fork.
我认为已经有几个月了。
and that is the kzd points evaluation and this is where it it's got some zk implications in it's
这就是KZD点评估，这就是它具有ZK的含义
got some vector commitment implications it's it's really it's an essential one but unless you're
得到了一些向量承诺的含义，这确实是必不可少的，但是除非您
using blobs it's really hard to explain really what it does but the short answer is it's used
使用斑点确实很难解释它的作用，但是简短的答案是使用
in blob proving that you have a certain field element in a blob that may or may not exist
在Blob中证明您在斑点中有某个可能存在或可能不存在的磁场元素
it goes entirely into the 4844.
它完全进入4844。
There's probably different presentation of 4844 that goes more deeper into it.
4844的陈述可能会更深入。
But as far as its role as a precompile, I think it shows an excellent example
但就其作为预编译的角色而言，我认为它显示了一个很好的例子
of a precompile that does very specialized computation that is very inefficient in
执行非常专业的计算的预编译非常效率非常低的计算
EVM, but very well understood and well implemented in an extra library.
EVM，但在额外的库中非常了解和实现。
If you want summaries of these, there is a website,
如果您想要这些摘要，则有一个网站
EVM Codes, in a precompile's page that gives a lot of the summary
EVM代码，在预编页的页面中提供了很多摘要
of all of these current pre-compiles do they have a prog page yet they don't have a product
在所有这些当前的预编译中，它们都有一个编写页面，但没有产品
page yet so i can't show you the um the proposed ones coming afterwards um but this has you know
page但是，我不能向你展示um之后提议的人，但这让你知道
all of the details into a lot of the various features that go into it um so let's go back to
所有细节都归入其中的许多功能，所以让我们回到
uh k view two bar
UH K查看两个吧台
So, when the EVM implements a pre-compile it's pretty simple.
因此，当EVM实施预编译时，这很简单。
The pre-compile just looks like any other contract it looks exactly like you're calling anything
预编译看起来就像其他任何合同看起来完全一样，就像您在打电话
else and this is actually part of the subtle design genius of a pre-compile it looks like
否则，这实际上是看起来像是预编译的微妙设计天才的一部分
you're calling another EVM contract but what happens you don't know you don't care about
您正在呼唤另一个EVM合同，但是发生了什么，您不知道您不在乎
you put the data in you get the data back it could be native it could be evm it just magically works
您将数据放入中获取数据，可能是本地的，它可能是EVM，它只是神奇地起作用
um and another essential feature of pre-compiles is that the gas cost is calculated entirely upon
UM和预编译的另一个基本特征是，完全计算出气体成本
the input data not on the actual executed gas which presents some challenges um if you pick
未在实际执行的气体上的输入数据，如果您选择的话，这会带来一些挑战
a particularly bad implementation of the pre-compile it's less efficient you can
预编译的一个特别糟糕的实现，您可以效率不高
slow down your vm but all the class costing is based entirely off of what it sees in the input
降低您的VM，但所有的班级成本都完全基于其在输入中看到的内容
it. And the return data is put in the return buffer or to output memory, depending upon how
它。并将返回数据放在返回缓冲区或输出内存中，具体取决于如何
you do the specific call. And it looks just exactly like any other contract call you would
您进行特定的电话。看起来就像其他任何合同电话一样
have out there. A couple of things, though, is that currently none of the proposed pre-compiles
在那里。但是，有几件事是目前没有提议的预编译
do deeper calls. They don't spawn further EVM calls. That's when Design Space has been explored
做更深入的电话。他们不会产生其他EVM呼叫。那是探索设计空间的时候
and rejected for, I think, 3074 initially started as pre-compiles, and they rejected that and went
我认为，拒绝3074最初是作为预编译而开始的，他们拒绝了这一点，然后去了
it's Opcos, because that just felt a little weird.
这是opcos，因为那感觉有些奇怪。
So typically, pre-compiled contracts
因此，通常，预编译合同
will just do stuff within themselves
只会在自己内部做事
and play on their own sandbox and return.
并在自己的沙盒上玩耍并返回。
It's not often that they're gonna interact
他们很少会互动
with the existing EVM environment,
在现有的EVM环境中，
and that presents security risks specifically.
并特别提出安全风险。
So, how are?
那么，怎么样？
So here's a deep example of what the ECE
因此，这是ECE的深刻例子
recovered pre-compile looks like.
恢复的预编译看起来像。
So the input is specified it's fixed to be,
因此，指定输入已固定为
128 bytes. And you got the commit hash, you got the V value, the R value, and the S value. And
128字节。然后您得到了提交哈希，您得到了V值，R值和S值。和
if you know a bit about EC-DSA, these will make a lot of sense to you. The commit hash is it,
如果您对EC-DSA有所了解，那么这些对您来说很有意义。提交是它，
EC-RECOVER only actually encrypts small amounts of data. So you would hash it down and encrypt
EC-Recover实际上仅加密少量数据。因此，您会将其放下并加密
that data. The V is actually something called a recovery ID, and it's encoded in 27 and 28 for
该数据。 V实际上是所谓的恢复ID，它在27和28中编码
historical reasons. But when you reverse, when you verify a signature, you get one of four values.
历史原因。但是，当您逆转时，当您验证签名时，您将获得四个值之一。
You get a value at negative infinity, at positive infinity, and then you get two different ones
您在正无穷大的无限无限的价值中获得了价值，然后您得到了两个不同的价值
at various points on the curve. This recover ID tells us which one to use to recover for the
在曲线上的各个点。此恢复ID告诉我们要恢复哪一个
address. And when you have your private key and you sign it, it'll wind up in one of those two,
地址。当您拥有私钥并签名时，它将在这两个中结束，
and you don't really know which one it's going to be until you do the signature. So that's why
而且，直到执行签名之前，您真的不知道它将是哪一个。这就是原因
bring that with it so the recovery id comes with the signature and we can verify it in one go other
随身携带它，因此恢复ID随签名带来
systems just say we'll just try all of them and if one of them matches you're good but that's
系统只会说我们只是尝试所有这些，如果其中一个与您匹配，那么您很好，但是那是
incredibly inefficient um and then the r value which is the value that you're encoding and the
效率低下的UM，然后是您编码的值的R值，
s value is some secret it's through the calculated values one part's calculated one part secret you
s值是一个秘密，它是通过计算值的一个部分计算的一个部分秘密
get one of these values reuse them you can ruin your key um the short answer is use a library
获得以下值之一重复使用它们，您可以毁了钥匙，um um简短的答案是使用库
to extract and use these um or get someone who is an expert on this to verify the code you write
提取和使用这些UM或找人是专家以验证您编写的代码
the return of course is just the lower 220 bytes of the 256 public key hash so it extracts the
当然，返回只是256个公钥哈希的较低220字节，因此它提取了
address and then it can check hashes it i think and then returns the lower 20 bytes of the hash
地址，然后可以检查我认为的哈斯，然后返回哈希的较低的20个字节
of the hash so then it's it's not a true um ecdsa key recovery it does it in a very ethereum centric
在哈希中，这不是真正的ECDSA密钥恢复，它以极为以太的为中心
in Ethereum-focused way.
以以太坊的方式。
And it serves Ethereum well,
它的服务很好，
because this is really focused on,
因为这确实专注于
did your address sign this value?
您的地址是否签署了此值？
So it really serves its purpose well.
因此，它确实实现了其目的。
The gas cost for this is $3,000,
这是3,000美元的汽油成本，
no matter what you do.
不管你做什么。
So it's a fixed increase.
因此，这是固定的增加。
But if we looked at some of the other contracts,
但是，如果我们查看其他一些合同，
we can see some of them have variable datas.
我们可以看到其中一些具有可变数据。
For example, ModXP is the most complex one.
例如，MODXP是最复杂的。
In fact, it's been revised by another EVM.
实际上，它已由另一个EVM进行了修订。
But some of the more simple ones are like EC pairing.
但是一些更简单的类似于EC配对。
How many pairs?
几对？
Okay, you take this and you multiply it.
好吧，您将其乘以它。
That's what your cost is.
那就是你的成本。
Blake 2F, how much data are you hashing?
Blake 2F，您藏了多少数据？
That's how much we're going to charge you.
那就是我们要收取多少费用。
And actually, Blake 2F is a bad example because you, again, do small amounts.
实际上，Blake 2F是一个糟糕的例子，因为您再次做少量。
Shot 256 is a better example.
射击256是一个更好的例子。
How much data are you hashing?
您散列多少数据？
And that's what we're going to charge you.
这就是我们要收取的。
Everything else here tends to have a fixed input size.
这里的其他所有内容往往具有固定的输入尺寸。
and that gets into some of the design considerations.
这涉及到一些设计考虑。
So that gets into some design issues
这样就陷入了一些设计问题
of when you're designing a pre-compile
当您设计预编译时
and these are some of the things
这些是一些事情
that have presented problems to clients before
以前向客户提出了问题
and to have delayed pre-compiles from being implemented.
并延迟了预编译的实施。
The first thing you need to do
您需要做的第一件事
if you're going to propose a pre-compile
如果您要提出预编译
is you need to make sure
您需要确保
all boundary conditions are specified.
所有边界条件均指定。
People are going to come,
人们会来的
it's not just the testers
不仅是测试人员
that are going to come in and try and break this.
那将进来并尝试打破这个。
Everyone's going to come in and try and break this.
每个人都会进来尝试打破这个。
Because there's, you know, attack strategies that involve in forking networks and causing problems in different forks.
因为您知道，攻击策略涉及分叉网络并在不同的叉子中引起问题。
Some of this is data, so it's mostly a proof of stake, a proof of work primary attack.
其中一些是数据，因此它主要是股份证明，这是工作原理攻击的证明。
But even a proof of stake, it causes, you know, causing the different clients to diverge on their system is pretty bad.
但是，即使是股份证明，它也会导致不同的客户在系统上差异。
So you need to make sure all boundary conditions are specified and they have a very specific way that they're going to be handled.
因此，您需要确保指定所有边界条件，并且它们具有非常具体的处理方式。
A second concern is that when you charge gas, you should make sure all gas scales with effort.
第二个问题是，当您为气体充电时，您应该确保所有的气体尺度努力。
Examples of this would be like the SHA-256, the MADI-XP, and the pairing checks.
这样的例子就像SHA-256，MADI-XP和配对检查一样。
The more difficult it is to get an answer, you should charge more gas for that.
得到答案的困难越困难，您应该为此收取更多的气体。
One of those is execution.
其中之一是执行。
Algorithms can hide some of these problems.
算法可以隐藏其中一些问题。
uh moddxp um has been you know there's been solutions we found to make sure everyone is
uh moddxp um，你知道有解决方案我们发现每个人都可以确保
under the current curve but there are some assumptions it's like well why would you
在当前曲线下，但是有一些假设，就像你为什么
ever want to do an even modulus that's kind of a dumb thing so all cryptography uses odd moduluses
曾经想做一个偶尔的模量，所以所有密码学都使用奇数模量
um except that you know it's not always cryptographers that are trying to cause
嗯，除了您知道并非总是是密码学家试图引起的
crazy things to happen um this is an issue also in things like um uh rsa signatures
疯狂的事情发生，嗯，这也是一个问题，例如UM UH RSA签名
But another thing is you want to have it also scale with the input.
但另一件事是您也想随着输入而扩展它。
So if you have a fixed amount of data, you want to make sure that your execution doesn't require parsing of all the data.
因此，如果您有固定量的数据，则要确保执行不需要解析所有数据。
So if someone passes in a megabyte of data, it doesn't blow up the execution of the precompile.
因此，如果有人通过数据兆字节，它不会炸毁预编译的执行。
The amount of data you pass in, you should always charge gas for each byte that comes in.
您传递的数据量，您应始终为每种字节的气体充电。
And if it's a variable amount, then your gas needs to be variable.
如果是可变量，则您的气体需要可变。
Now, I think that finally, the last example of a worst case is that you should account for the worst case.
现在，我认为最后，最坏情况的最后一个例子是您应该考虑最坏的情况。
It's tempting just to cost it for the typical case to make sure that everyone gets a fair use.
诱人的只是为了为典型的情况而花费，以确保每个人都有合理的利用。
It's like, you know, you're only going to use moddxp for odd moduluses, and you're only going to do it for within a certain range.
就像，您知道，您只会将MODDXP用于奇数模量，而您只会在一定范围内使用它。
But some people are going to use absurdly large numbers, and they're going to use even moduluses, just for no other reason than to try and troll the chain.
但是有些人将使用荒谬的数字，他们将使用甚至模量，只是因为尝试拖链而不是其他原因。
This happened back in DebCon2 in Shanghai.
这发生在上海的DebCon2中。
There are people that were trolling the chain.
有些人在拖链。
Some people do it for fun.
有些人是为了好玩的。
Some people do it for money.
有些人是为了钱而做的。
But you should just expect in anything that you design in a protocol layer
但是您应该只期望在协议层中设计的任何内容中
that people are going to try and attack it regardless of their motivation.
人们将尝试攻击它，无论他们的动力如何。
It's something that you need to be prepared to handle
这是您需要做好准备的东西
and something that you need to be prepared to implement.
以及您需要准备实施的东西。
So let's dive into some of the questions about how it's implemented.
因此，让我们深入了解有关其实施方式的一些问题。
I see some of the questions coming in some of the chat room.
我看到一些聊天室中出现的一些问题。
So, so one of the questions is, actually, this is going to be on the next slide, implementation
因此，因此，问题之一是，实际上，这将是下一个幻灯片，实施
strategies.
策略。
I'll go and answer this really quick.
我会很快回答这个问题。
One question is referring to basis or precompile codes implemented inside the Java virtual
一个问题是指Java虚拟内实施的基础或预编码代码
machine.
机器。
Are they being done in another process the Java virtual machine is calling?
它们是在Java虚拟机正在调用的另一个过程中完成的吗？
Kind of.
有点儿。
Some precompiles are done in Java, if they're like, like the identity is really simple.
某些预编译是在Java中完成的，如果它们就像，例如身份真的很简单。
But some of the more expensive ones like ECDSA, we don't call it to it in the process.
但是，一些更昂贵的eCDA，例如ECDSA，我们在此过程中不称呼它。
But we do bring in a different library into Java.
但是我们确实将另一个图书馆带入Java。
We actually, in Basu, we use the Bitcoin, Bitcoin D, there's a library that Bitcoin D uses.
实际上，在巴苏，我们使用比特币D比特币D，有一个比特币D使用的库。
And it's got some, there's something about the K curve that provides for some really fast calculation of it that, you know, again, I don't fully understand the math.
它有一些，K曲线有一些非常快速的计算，您再知道，我不完全了解数学。
I just know it's faster.
我只知道它更快。
So we bring that solution in.
因此，我们将该解决方案带入。
It's just something fundamental about the way that they implement the algorithm.
这只是他们实施算法的方式。
And that gets us faster time on calculating it.
这使我们可以更快地计算它。
I think all clients use this.
我认为所有客户都使用此。
If they don't use the specific piece of software from Bitcoin D, at the very least, they use the algorithms there to make it faster.
如果他们不使用比特币D的特定软件，至少他们会使用那里的算法来更快。
So both things are done, implemented either in raw Java or use an external library.
因此，这两个事情都完成了，在RAW Java中实现或使用外部库。
We don't have the bit where we go out to a separate process to execute it.
我们没有进入单独的过程执行它的位置。
I think that's more some of the more exotic design approaches out there.
我认为这是一些更奇特的设计方法。
And if that gets reported on a pre-compile, what's the plan of action?
而且，如果在预编译中报告了这是什么行动计划？
I'll come to that question at the end.
最后我会提出这个问题。
That is an excellent question from Rahul.
这是拉胡尔的一个很好的问题。
So let's mark that for it
所以让我们为此标记
and we get into Q&A session.
我们参加了问答环节。
So let's look at a brief
所以让我们看一个简介
of how it's implemented.
如何实施。
I found in the four major clients
我在四个主要客户中发现
that are out there,
那在那里，
for Aragon, I'm kind of punting
对于阿拉贡，我有点刺
because Aragon, when it comes
因为阿拉贡，当它到来时
to non-data storage things,
到非数据存储事物，
is mostly Geth under the covers currently.
目前主要是Geth的封面。
They're working on bringing in
他们正在努力引进
something called Silkworm,
所谓的蚕，
but that's not production level yet.
但这还不是生产水平。
So, you know, there's some interesting
所以，你知道，有一些有趣的
things going on in Aragon.
阿拉贡发生的事情。
But for now, they're going
但是现在，他们要去
it mostly reflected in the way geth works.
它主要反映了Geth的工作方式。
Starting out in BASU,
从巴苏开始，
BASU implements all of these in
巴苏在
the Java package based on EVM pre-compile.
基于EVM预编译的Java软件包。
You can see all the different pre-compiles we have out there.
您可以看到我们那里的所有不同的预编译。
So let's ID pre-compile contracts pretty simple one.
因此，让我们ID预编译合同非常简单。
It has a simple interfaces,
它具有简单的接口，
what's the gas requirement,
什么是气体要求，
and how do you compute the pre-compile?
以及如何计算预编译？
It's pretty simple stuff.
这是非常简单的东西。
Here, this is the most simple pre-compile we have out there,
在这里，这是我们那里最简单的预编译，
you just copy it. Of course it's Java,
您只需复制它。当然是Java，
it's Hyperledger where there's lots of
这是Hyperledger，那里有很多
boilerplate and Java-isms, and it's done in a very Java way.
样板和爪哇主义，它以非常爪哇的方式完成。
Now, if you want to see it done in a very Go way,
现在，如果您想以一定的方式看到它，
we have Get's approach to it, which suddenly is not found.
我们有了它的方法，突然找不到。
This is so awesome.
这太棒了。
Core VM contracts.
核心VM合同。
Did they just move this?
他们只是移动了吗？
It must be a particular branch that they got rid of.
它一定是他们摆脱的特定分支。
So core VM contracts, here they have all of their pre-compiles implemented.
因此，核心VM合同，在这里，他们已经实施了所有预编译。
And you also see in Go's code, in Geth's code, how they separate it based on the various generations of when they might use these contracts, whether it's Byzantium, Istanbul, Berlin, Cancun.
而且，您还可以根据Geth的代码在Geth的代码中看到它们如何根据它们使用这些合同的各个世代将其分开，无论是拜占庭，伊斯坦布尔，柏林，坎昆。
And they bring in some of the PROG pre-compiles that are also being brought in with the BLS signatures that are needed.
他们引入了一些前进的预编译，这些预编译也带有所需的BLS签名。
and go is a bit simpler it's very get this very much more go-like in the way that they handle it
而Go更简单，它可以使他们能够处理它的方式更像
um they define a structure here's some constants they define their methods on the structure that's
嗯，他们定义了一个结构，这里有一些常数，他们在结构上定义了他们的方法
big that's not what i'm looking for and they implement an interface you know in this case
大于我要寻找的东西，它们在这种情况下实现了您知道的界面
it's required gas and then it'll actually run it it's the same thing you get the bytes you get the
它是必需的气，然后实际上运行它，这是您得到的，您得到的
gas and mod exp is probably the most complex one to calculate the gas cost for um you get into
气体和mod exp可能是计算您进入的气体成本的最复杂的exp
other ones required gas it just returns a fixed value for example for the bm-256 add it's always
其他需要的气体它只是返回固定值，例如BM-256添加它始终
the same value because we're always adding two things and um it gets to run there is a separate
相同的价值，因为我们总是添加两件事，并且它可以运行有一个独立的
library that they use for their bm stuff um and again it does you know it's implemented in go
他们用于BM东西的库，您知道它是在GO中实现的
The VM libraries in Go are good enough.
GO中的VM库足够好。
In doing it in Java, we farm out to a Rust library,
在Java做这件事时，我们耕种到一个生锈图书馆，
because it's faster, primarily.
因为它更快，主要是。
When you do bit twiddling,
当你有点扭曲时，
you don't want to do bit twiddling in Go.
您不想在Go中做一点扭曲。
Nethermind, they have a pre-compile CS,
Nethermind，他们有一个预编译CS，
so let's go to, let's see,
因此，让我们去看看，看看，
EC Recover's probably a good one.
EC恢复可能是一个很好的选择。
But again, they have the same similar approach.
但是，他们也有相同的方法。
They store it in a very C-sharp way.
他们以非常c-sharp的方式存储它。
They need to store their address as metadata.
他们需要将地址存储为元数据。
You calculate the gas cost, the base cast cost.
您计算气体成本，基本铸造成本。
You run it.
你运行它。
You execute the data.
您执行数据。
So in main net, a lot of these precompiles are just kind of boring
因此，在主要网络中，许多这些预编译只是有点无聊
because they're just doing boring math that we need to have done efficiently.
因为他们只是在做无聊的数学，我们需要有效地做到这一点。
Let's do the ECU recovery here in ref to show a very similar type situation.
让我们在此处进行ECU恢复，以显示非常相似的情况。
You have the actual function that does it.
您具有可以执行此操作的实际功能。
Do they have the gas cost in here?
他们在这里有汽油成本吗？
They have gas limit, the gas costing.
它们具有气体限制，气体成本量。
Yeah, REF does a slightly different approach.
是的，裁判采取了略有不同的方法。
They include the gas usage with the output.
它们包括带有输出的气体使用情况。
So they have the results of how much gas costs, and they actually output bytes.
因此，他们的成本成本是多少，并且实际上输出了字节。
So they do it in one go.
所以他们一次去做。
Some of us split it up into two steps.
我们中的一些人将其分为两个步骤。
Some of us do it in one go.
我们中有些人一次去做。
And that has some design implications.
这具有一些设计含义。
If you can tell from the gas that they don't have enough gas to execute this gigantic modd xp before you even try to execute it, you need to just say, hey, there's not enough gas.
如果您可以从气体中告诉他们，他们甚至在尝试执行它之前没有足够的汽油来执行巨大的MODD XP，那么您只需要说，嘿，没有足够的汽油。
I'm not even going to try. Consume all the gas and return.
我什至不会尝试。消耗所有汽油并返回。
Otherwise, that's a security attack if you can force people to waste effort when you don't have enough gas.
否则，如果您可以在没有足够的汽油时迫使人们浪费努力，那就是安全攻击。
And that's something that's pretty well trodden paths in some of the security auditors and researchers who go through and fuzz and figure these things out.
在一些安全审计师和研究人员中，这是一个很好的路径，他们经历了并弄脏并弄清楚了这些事情。
So it's pretty well understood that you check your gas before you do anything expensive.
因此，非常了解您在做任何昂贵的事情之前先检查汽油。
And there's multiple ways to get that wrong.
而且有多种方法可以解决这一问题。
And that's something auditors always look at.
这是审计师一直在看的东西。
So like I said, implementation strategies, you can do it with native code.
因此，就像我说的，实施策略，您可以使用本机代码来完成。
If it is fast enough for implementation, if you want faster code, typically you'll go to a custom written library.
如果它足够快地实现，则需要更快的代码，通常会转到自定义书面库。
that they really, I mean, the ECDSA code for the 256K1 curve,
我的意思是，它们的确是256K1曲线的ECDSA代码，
they have written Intel and ARM machine code
他们已经写了英特尔和手臂机代码
to try and get this as blazing fast as possible.
尝试尽可能快地将其燃烧。
Because in Bitcoin, it makes sense for them
因为在比特币中，对他们来说很有意义
because that is their singular longest path
因为那是他们最长的路径
is validating these hashes.
正在验证这些哈希。
That is the most expensive part of Bitcoin.
那是比特币中最昂贵的部分。
So it makes a lot of sense for them
所以对他们来说很有意义
to just go crazy in implementing it and optimizing it.
只是疯狂地实施并优化它。
And we just got to reap the benefits.
而且我们只需要获得好处。
It's pretty awesome there.
那里很棒。
So a question from Kira.
因此来自基拉的问题。
Can you discuss some specific ways in which precompiles reduce gaskots compared to implementing similar functionalities in pure solidity?
与在纯固体中实现相似的功能相比，您能否讨论一些特定的方法来减少燃气机？
Any code optimization that's most commonly used in precompiles?
预编码中最常用的任何代码优化吗？
So probably the biggest thing in implementing it is why a lot of these cryptographic things are done outside of EVM.
因此，实施最大的事情可能是为什么在EVM之外完成许多这些加密事件的原因。
is because the EVM is a 256-bit stack machine.
是因为EVM是一台256位堆栈机。
Every word that goes on there is 256 bits,
每个词都有256位，
but some of these operations are fine,
但是其中一些操作很好，
like in Kachak in particular, use smaller bits,
特别是在Kachak中，使用较小的位，
or they have definitions that are really pliable
或者他们的定义确实很柔软
to vector operations, single input, no,
到向量操作，单个输入，否，
multiple instructions, single data, single,
多个说明，单个数据，单个，
multiple data, single instruction.
多个数据，单个指令。
S-I-M-D. Got to go back to my undergrad classes to get that out.
S-I-M-D。 Got to go back to my undergrad classes to get that out.
But they're really amenable to being put in vector optimizations.
But they're really amenable to being put in vector optimizations.
And then some of these, like the mod EXP, they need to use a variable width number that could potentially go up to completely unbound sizes of numbers.
然后，其中一些（例如Mod Exp）需要使用一个可能会增加数字大小的可变宽度数。
That's one class of bugs that the Geth famously found.
That's one class of bugs that the Geth famously found.
When they were fuzzing Geth, it goes biggest number if you use absurdly large numbers.
当他们模糊的Geth时，如果您使用荒谬的数字，它将达到最大的数量。
I mean, even larger than what you would think is absurdly large numbers in some of their libraries, you could segfault go.
我的意思是，甚至比您认为的某些库中荒谬的数字还要大，您可以使用Segfault。
And I think a particular bug they found is from that they were able to lever that.
而且我认为他们发现的一个特殊的错误是他们能够利用这一点。
And then if they could put a RSA signature certificate and they claimed that one of their fields was that large and they put the number in that was that large, it would segfault it.
然后，如果他们可以放置RSA签名证书，他们声称他们的一个领域很大，并且将数字放在那样大，那将是将其弄清楚。
So from some of these, you know, fuzzing efforts,
因此，从其中一些，您知道的努力，
they figured out a way to take down SSL servers just because they're trying to
他们想出了一种方法来删除SSL服务器，只是因为他们试图
fuzz their geth implementation. So there's,
他们的Geth实施。所以有
that was a pretty big win from, from geth.
这是Geth的巨大胜利。
And so, yeah, so that's it for, for precompile contracts.
因此，是的，就是这样，为预编译合同。
I'm doing this for the purpose of, of, of efficiency,
我是出于，效率的目的，
but the biggest reason why you wouldn't want to do it in EVM code is because
但是您不想在EVM代码中这样做的最大原因是因为
it's much faster to do it natively.
本地进行操作要快得多。
When you're building blocks and when you're trying to find MEV solutions, you want to do this absolutely as fast as possible.
当您建立障碍物以及尝试找到MEV解决方案时，您希望绝对快速执行此操作。
So not only is it faster, but it's also cheaper in gas.
因此，它不仅更快，而且气体也更便宜。
Almost every single one of these precompiles, they're defined.
这些预编译中的几乎每个都定义了。
They have a very efficient, very hard-to-achieve gas cost to do in EVM.
它们在EVM中的效率非常高，非常难以达成的天然气成本。
I don't think any of these, you could code an EVM version of these that would beat the gas cost that's scheduled here.
我认为这些都不是，您可以编码这些EVM版本，以超过此处计划的气体成本。
And the gas cost is meant to mirror the actual machine execution cost of executing those.
气体成本旨在反映出执行这些的实际机器执行成本。
So the next thing I want to talk about is system contracts.
因此，我要谈论的下一件事是系统合同。
I'd like to take this Star Wars quote and twist it because it's kind of true.
我想以这个《星球大战》的报价并扭曲它，因为它是真的。
System contracts are pathway to many capabilities that some consider to be unaligned.
系统合同是某些人认为不一致的许多功能的途径。
Some of these things done in system contracts will never see the light of day in mainnet because it's not sufficiently pure.
在系统合同中完成的其中一些事情将永远不会在主网中看到一天的光芒，因为它不够纯净。
Pure might be the wrong word.
纯正可能是错误的词。
But it's doing things that Mainnet doesn't need to do
但这是在做主网不需要做的事情
and Mainnet doesn't want to do.
主网不想做。
But it's doing things that some of these Layer 2s
但这是在做这些第2层中的一些
and all Layer 1s have to do.
所有第1层都必须做。
There's no other efficient way to do it.
没有其他有效的方法可以做到。
So what are system contracts?
那么什么是系统合同？
Where are these being used?
这些在哪里使用？
A lot of the typical uses for these
这些典型用途
are for accessing L1 and L2 bridging.
用于访问L1和L2桥接。
Arbitrum, Optimism, and the various ZK chains
仲裁，乐观和各种ZK链
use these system contracts.
use these system contracts.
Some of them use a hybrid pre-deployed contract
Some of them use a hybrid pre-deployed contract
or deployed contract,
or deployed contract,
and they use events to signal into it.
and they use events to signal into it.
But these contracts,
But these contracts,
Arbitrum uses a direct native implementation
仲裁使用直接实施
of these contracts, even specify it and go it.
在这些合同中，甚至可以指定并进行。
They got some fancy compiler stuff to work with that.
他们有一些花哨的编译器可以使用。
And there's a spelling error on this.
而且有一个拼写错误。
You know I wrote this.
你知道我写了这篇文章。
I know that's spelled wrong.
我知道那是错误的。
I'll fix this when I bring the slides out later.
稍后将幻灯片带出时，我将修复此问题。
But layer one, layer two bridging,
但是第一层，第二层桥接，
there's a lot of issues with maintaining the bridge
维护桥梁有很多问题
from layer one, layer two.
从第一层，第二层。
That can really only be done
真的只能完成
from authorized from within the EVM.
从EVM内部授权。
we can only be acted on outside the EVM in the L2 node software.
我们只能在L2节点软件中的EVM之外作用。
So this is what I consider those system contracts,
这就是我认为这些系统合同的原因，
even the ones that are done entirely in EVM and signal through events,
即使是完全在EVM中完成并通过事件发出信号的人，
I consider those system contracts just a different variety.
我认为这些系统合同只是不同的种类。
And I can put them in the pre-compile scan.
我可以将它们放入预编译扫描中。
Another reason you might want to do that is you might want to host,
您可能想这样做的另一个原因是您可能想托管，
access foreign chain services.
访问外国连锁服务。
Three examples that I have here are Moonbeam.
我在这里有三个例子是Moonbeam。
Moonbeam is an EVM implementation on top of Polkadot.
Moonbeam是Polkadot之上的EVM实施。
Aurora. Aurora is an EVM implementation on top of Near. And Hedera. And Hedera has implemented
极光。 Aurora是近距离的EVM实施。和Hedera。 Hedera已实施
a smart contract service, but underneath the smart contract service, Hedera has a very different
智能合约服务，但在智能合约服务下，Hedera的差异很大
token system and accounting system. So the system contracts can be used in these instances
令牌系统和会计系统。因此，系统合同可以在这些情况下使用
to access the native tokens in their systems as their native tokens, or do native actions
访问其系统中的本地令牌作为本机代币，或进行本机操作
on their accounts as needed um see moonbeams um pretty compiled contracts i mean it's it's
在他们的帐户上，根据需要看到Moonbeams um漂亮的合同，我的意思是
used a way to get to substrates and there's lots of things that are very polka dot specific that
使用一种方法来延伸到底物，并且有很多非常多的圆点特定的东西
you might want to um go in and do that related to polka dot um because polka dot's famous for things
您可能想进入并做与波尔卡圆点有关的事情
like um it's got it's dow voting features in there it's got its own uh token um moonbeams implemented
就像嗯，它有DOW投票功能，它拥有自己的uh token um moonbeams
it its own token system, relaying things between the different chains, cross-chain communication.
它自己的代币系统，在不同的链条之间传达东西，跨链通信。
And these are accessed via pre-compiled contracts in Moonbeam. So it looks like you're calling just
这些是通过Moonbeam中预编译合同访问的。所以看来您只是在打电话
another EVM contract, but we're actually escaping the EVM, and we're going in and we're using
另一份EVM合同，但我们实际上是在逃脱EVM，我们要去了，我们正在使用
features from other host systems that are not typical to EVM. I think Near's got mostly the
EVM并非典型的其他主机系统的功能。我认为附近的大部分是
same sort of things that they're doing on there. Again, they canonize the existing smart contracts
他们在那里做的同样的事情。同样，他们将现有的智能合约供
that exist there. And then they bring in all the other sorts of things that they would need to do
那里存在。然后他们带来了他们需要做的所有其他事情
into NEAR. They're specific to the way that Aurora integrates with NEAR. They have their own.
进入附近。它们特定于Aurora与附近集成的方式。他们有自己的。
And what's interesting about the way that NEAR does it is their addresses don't map to the
而且，关于其地址的靠近的方式有趣的是没有映射到
pre-compile addresses. They have specific reasons why these addresses serve here. They don't use
预编译地址。他们有这些地址在这里服务的具体原因。他们不使用
create or create2 to bring these or create transactions, but they have their own mechanisms
创建或创建2来带来或创建交易，但它们有自己的机制
to determine what the address is. And this is just how it happens to map onto Ethereum.
确定地址是什么。这就是将其映射到以太坊的方式。
And Hedera, they have their, one of the big things they have is a token service.
和Hedera，他们拥有他们拥有的重要一件是代币的服务。
They have their own native tokens and Hedera wants to expose it so they look like ERC-20 tokens.
他们有自己的本地令牌，而Hedera想要揭露它，因此看起来像ERC-20令牌。
So this is, you know, one part of the contract where you treat the token service normally.
因此，这就是您正常对待令牌服务的合同的一部分。
And there is another set of pre-compiled contracts that exist at the addresses of where the Hedera tokens would be that booster this into this contract and then go into and do all their specialized Hedera stuff.
在Hedera代币将在此合同中添加此合同，然后进入并完成所有专业的Hedera工作，还有另一套预编译合同。
And they also expose it here.
他们也在这里暴露了它。
There are some things that are very Hedera specific that you can still go into this contract if you need things that, you know, they got token fee system that Ethereum will never add.
有些事情非常具体，如果您需要以太坊永远不会添加的令牌费系统，您仍然可以签订此合同。
but this token fee system is baked into Hedera.
但是，这个令牌费系统被烘烤到Hedera中。
So this provides an escape hatch when you access it
因此，当您访问它时，这提供了一个逃生舱口
as though it's a system contract
好像这是系统合同
to get into these features
进入这些功能
without having to change the nature of Ethereum.
不必改变以太坊的本质。
And the final thing, I mentioned this earlier,
最后一件事，我之前提到过
a couple of names worth mentioning
值得一提的几个名字
are Phoenix and Ritual.
是凤凰和仪式。
And I'm sure there's,
我敢肯定
I think there's a few other FAT people out there
我认为那里还有其他一些胖子
and there's other AI models,
还有其他AI模型，
but those are the two names that came to mind
但是那是想到的两个名字
that had interactions with them before.
以前与他们进行了互动。
But they're going to be using pre-compiles to access things that are completely foreign to host chains, and they're completely foreign to Layer 1s and Layer 2s.
但是，他们将使用预编译来访问完全外国链条的事物，并且它们完全是陌生的，对于第1层和第2层。
Fully homomorphic encryption is really neat.
完全同态加密真的很整洁。
You can encrypt a number.
您可以加密一个数字。
You can encrypt another number.
您可以加密另一个数字。
From this encrypted data, you can do an operation that says add these two numbers together, and you have no idea what the result is unless you have the key that can decrypt it.
从这些加密数据中，您可以执行一个操作，说将这两个数字添加在一起，并且您不知道结果是什么，除非您有可以解密它的键。
So you can have everyone put in all these numbers.
因此，您可以让所有人都投入所有这些数字。
You can say, like, you're doing a Dutch auction.
您可以说，就像在进行荷兰拍卖。
Everyone can put in their bid, and then you can do comparisons against each other to figure out what the clearing point is.
每个人都可以投入出价，然后您可以相互比较，以找出清除点是什么。
And then you can reveal that number, and nobody knows what your bids are.
然后您可以揭示这个数字，没人知道您的出价是什么。
The downside to this is, in addition to being lattice-based math that is really a bit twiddly and difficult in EVM,
不利的一面是，除了基于晶格的数学外，EVM确实有点扭曲和困难，
the data can be kilobytes and megabytes large to do some of these features that they need to do in the fully homomorphic encryption.
这些数据可以是千数键和大型兆字节，可以在完全同态加密中执行其中需要做的一些功能。
I think it's also quantum safe, which is another neat feature, but you can't pass around megabytes of data.
我认为它也是量子安全的，这是另一个整洁的功能，但是您无法传递大量数据。
So they're going to, you know, they're going to handle it their own way, but they're going to use pre-compile contracts to access that.
因此，他们将要以自己的方式处理它，但是他们将使用预编译合同来访问这一点。
And that's like an entirely different service that you wouldn't want to put in the EVM, but you can still manipulate it through a pre-compile contract.
这就像您不想在EVM中投入的完全不同的服务，但是您仍然可以通过预编译合同来操纵它。
Ritual, I don't know as much about what they're planning.
仪式，我对他们的计划不太了解。
I don't think it's quite as firmed up, but they're planning, proposing on doing the same things.
我认为这不是很坚定，但是他们正在计划，建议做同样的事情。
you could take some information, you could have an AI model, and you could say, you know,
您可以获取一些信息，可以拥有AI模型，并且可以说，您知道，
with this prompt, what do I get out of it? Whether you're asking for, you know, a large language
有了这个提示，我能从中得到什么？无论您是要问的是一种大语言
model, or whether you're asking for like some sort of a financial projection, or some other AI
模型，还是您是否要求某种财务投影或其他AI
thing that you might want from it. Those are things you would not want to put typically,
您可能想要的东西。这些是您通常不想放的东西，
there's no way you could put an LLM in EVM and run it in a reasonable amount of time,
您无法在EVM中放置LLM并在合理的时间内运行它，
just the matrix math you would do there. And you couldn't store it in the EVM efficiently.
只是矩阵数学，您会在那里进行。而且您无法有效地将其存储在EVM中。
So they're going to have a system where people are going to go out and execute it and put it on there and batch for it.
因此，他们将拥有一个系统，人们将出去执行它，然后将其放在那里并批处理它。
And there's going to be some ways to check it.
并且将有一些检查它的方法。
And the way they're going to access that is through pre-compiled contracts.
以及他们将通过预先编译合同访问的方式。
Again, pre-compiled contracts are the escape hatch to do things that you would never dream of doing in EVM because it's the wrong place to do it.
同样，预编译合同是做您永远不会梦想在EVM中做的事情的逃生舱口，因为这是错误的地方。
But you need to get access to things on chain if you want to have crypto economic incentives about it.
但是，如果您想对此有加密经济激励措施，则需要访问链上的事物。
So it's how you can bridge these two areas and still have the power of FHE or AI models, and yet still come back in and still add those features in and still have the crypto economic incentives.
因此，这是您可以桥接这两个领域并仍然具有FHE或AI模型的力量的方式，但仍然重新添加并仍然添加这些功能，并且仍然具有加密经济激励措施。
So talking about L2s, in addition to EVM codes, another one of the sites that I love to look at to get information about this is rollup.codes.
因此，除了EVM代码外，谈论L2S，我喜欢查看的另一个网站以获取有关此信息的信息是rollup.codes。
This is a service that Limechain put together, worked with them before.
这是Limechain提供的服务，以前与他们合作。
They're great guys and girls, ladies.
女士们，他们是伟人和女孩。
Sorry, I got the words wrong.
抱歉，我的话错误。
But they're a great bunch of engineers to work with.
但是他们是一大堆可以与之合作的工程师。
And they put all this together.
他们把所有这些都放在一起。
And right now, this just focuses on L2s.
现在，这只是关注L2。
But you can get all the information on the various system contracts that come in L2s.
但是您可以获取有关L2S中各种系统合同的所有信息。
Because, you know, Arbitrum has a small amount of them.
因为，您知道，仲裁的数量很少。
And it's interesting, you can link in here.
有趣的是，您可以在这里链接。
They link into the actual implementation.
它们链接到实际实施中。
So Arbitrum does their system contracts in Go.
因此，仲裁会在旅途中签订合同。
Or you can go back to, you know, Optimus.
或者，您可以回到擎天柱。
and we'll use the canonical optimism chain
我们将使用规范的乐观链
to show some of these.
显示其中一些。
They have, you know, quite a few more,
您知道，他们还有很多
and they do their own special things,
他们做自己的特殊事情，
like L2, L1 message passer.
像L2一样，L1消息传球。
Again, these links have died.
同样，这些链接已经死亡。
Packages, contracts, bedrock.
包裹，合同，基岩。
Move to source, L2, yeah, they moved it around.
转到Source，L2，是的，他们将其移动。
So L2 to one message passer,
所以l2到一个消息传递人，
And here you can see that they've implemented these, and this is worth probably a little bit of a drill down on it, and that this is a very viable approach to do your system contract integrations.
在这里，您可以看到他们已经实施了这些，这可能值得一点点钻探，这是进行系统合同集成的一种非常可行的方法。
This is all implemented in EVM, and I don't think they have specific code to implement this specifically.
这一切都是在EVM中实施的，我认为他们没有具体的代码来具体实施。
This is probably a boring one to look at.
这可能是一个无聊的东西。
you want to go to some more universal stuff.
您想去一些更多通用的东西。
But like, so, you know, their base vVault,
但是，就像，你知道，他们的基本vvault，
it refers to vVault and i7 version.
它指VVAULT和i7版本。
So let's go back to the universal
所以让我们回到环球
and go into their vVault code.
并进入他们的Vvault代码。
And, you know, all the stuff that you would do
而且，您知道，您会做的所有事情
is expressed in solidity.
以坚固性表示。
But what they do is they will emit events
但是他们要做的是发出事件
and this will signal to the L2 node
这会发出信号向L2节点
a withdrawal has been done.
已经取出了。
And so you localize some of your security model within the EVM itself.
因此，您将某些安全模型本地定位在EVM本身中。
And if a particular event comes from a particular address, you just have trust that it's actually what's supposed to happen.
而且，如果特定事件来自特定的地址，您只是相信这实际上是应该发生的事情。
You've got to trust that the EVM does what it says it does.
您必须相信EVM会做它所说的事情。
And so based on that information, you would then do all of your bookkeeping on your side to change the various states.
因此，基于这些信息，您将在您身边进行所有簿记以更改各种状态。
And then these are communicated via events.
然后通过事件传达这些内容。
and zket EVMs tend to do this a lot too
和Zket EVMS也倾向于这样做
for a lot of their signaling.
他们的许多信号。
Let's see, one of the more vanilla ones.
让我们看看，这是更香草的之一。
I think Polygon links to their code here.
我认为多边形在这里链接到他们的代码。
And Polygon is interesting.
多边形很有趣。
It's another interesting design choice.
这是另一个有趣的设计选择。
It's all in one giant contract.
这全都是一份巨型合同。
But again, here you'll see that there's going to be
但是，再次，在这里您会发现会有
and they got a lot of their events here
他们在这里有很多活动
of how they're communicating back and forth,
他们如何来回交流，
claims and bridgings.
索赔和布里奇。
And again, it focuses on using the emit
再一次，它重点是使用发射机
to calculate the information.
计算信息。
So, you know, things they'll do, L2, L1 communications,
因此，您知道，他们会做的事情，L2，L1通信，
managing their money and their fee vaults,
管理他们的钱和收费保险柜，
bridging, of course, is part of this implicitly.
当然，桥接是隐含的一部分。
Security admin tasks, if you manage your rights
安全管理任务，如果您管理自己的权利
to your L2 stuff to various addresses,
到您的L2东西到各种地址，
they'll use the system contracts to update that might be stored in in in the uh in the evm state
他们将使用系统合同来更新可能存储在EVM状态的UH中
it might be stored in the l2 node state but it's it goes through an ev through a pre-compile system
它可能存储在L2节点状态中，但它通过EV通过预编译系统
contract um but what's interesting is some things are doing is that chain info queries are also
合同嗯，但是有趣的是有些事情是链条信息查询也是
being done through pre-compiles and this is something that i kind of wish layer one would
通过预编译完成，这是我的希望层
start moving towards rather than creating a new op code every time you have a new blob base v
每当您拥有新的Blob base V时，就开始朝向而不是创建新的OP代码
or some other chain-specific data,
或其他一些特定于链的数据，
they go through smart,
他们经历了聪明的
they do go through pre-compilers
他们确实经历了预互换者
because, you know,
因为，你知道，
that would make all of the opcodes
那将使所有的opcodes
very, very difficult to use
非常非常困难
because every system
因为每个系统
would have their own custom opcode
将有自己的自定义opcode
and there's no way Solidity and Viper
而且没有牢固性和毒蛇
and everyone else
还有其他所有人
would support all those features.
将支持所有这些功能。
So a lot of these kind of duplicate
所以很多这样的重复
what goes on in the 30 to 40 chain.
30至40链中发生的事情。
And some of these are new,
其中一些是新的，
unique things specific to the way
特定方式的独特事物
that the various L2s work
各种L2工作
because the notion of your L2 block
因为您的L2块的概念
and your L1 block being different
和您的L1块不同
is something that's completely foreign
是完全外国的东西
to Ethereum mainnet.
到以太坊主网。
Now, in going through this,
现在，经历这一点，
you can see some notable design choices
您可以看到一些值得注意的设计选择
in the way the L2 contracts
以L2合同的方式
handle their precompiles
处理他们的预编译
versus the way Ethereum mainnet wants.
与以太坊主网想要的方式相对于。
Almost universally,
几乎普遍
all things that are not Ethereum mainnet,
所有不是以太坊的事物，
especially when they're in layer twos,
尤其是当他们在两层二层时，
is that they're using the Solidity API
是他们使用的是固体API
for the precompiled access.
用于预编译的访问。
In mainnet, each address does one thing
在主网中，每个地址做一件事
and it does one thing only,
而且它只能做一件事，
it does one thing well but if we did that for um pre-compiles and um yeah i'll get that that's a
它做得很好，但是如果我们为um预编译而做到这一点，嗯，我会得到那是一个
good question is there eaps for new pre-compiles that are currently being considered i'll come back
一个好问题，目前正在考虑的新预编译有EAPS，我会回来
back to that q a that's a great question um but as far as um if we have one pre-compile for each
回到该Q A，这是一个很好的问题，但是至今我们都有一个预编译
address there would be like thousands of pre-compiles hundreds of thousands of free
地址将有成千上万的预编译
compiles in some of these layer two systems and it'd be hard to figure out what's going on with
在第二层系统中的某些系统中编译，很难弄清楚发生了什么
it. And a lot of these contract developers are used to understanding and reading the Solidity
它。这些合同开发人员中有很多被用来理解和阅读坚固性
documentation to figure out what's supposed to be going on with it. So it's kind of become,
文档以弄清楚应该发生的事情。所以有点变得
Solidity ABI has kind of become a default interface for messaging between the two layers.
坚固的ABI已成为两层之间传递消息传递的默认接口。
And this begs the question, maybe we need an ERC to canonize a Solidity ABI separate from Solidity.
这就提出了一个问题，也许我们需要一个ERC来构成坚固的ABI与坚固性分开。
I don't know how Solidity would feel about it, but it's being used in Viper, it's being used in
我不知道对此有多坚固，但是它被用于毒蛇，它被用于
lots of different places, I think it's worth elevating it to its own standard that is separate.
许多不同的地方，我认为值得将其提升为独立的标准。
But there's also some mixed API decisions in how they implement it. Some Layer 2s use multiple
但是，它们如何实施它也有一些混合的API决定。某些第2层使用多个
contracts. Some ZK systems use one giant contract to do everything. That's just how far you split
合同。一些ZK系统使用一份巨型合同来完成所有操作。那就是你分裂多远
it apart. There's no real consistency on that. And at the end of the day, it's the design
它分开。这没有真正的一致性。归根结底，这是设计
preference on how you like to do that as the implementer. There's a mixed permanence in some
偏爱您想如何作为实施者做到这一点。有些人有混合的持久性
these contracts. Some operate through proxies, and some are fixed deployment. Again, there's
这些合同。有些是通过代理运行的，有些是固定部署的。再次有
preferences to how you want to expose your security risks on that. There's also mixed
偏爱您如何在此公开安全风险。也有很多
implementation strategies. Some chains implement their system contracts directly in the node
实施策略。有些连锁直接在节点中实施他们的系统合同
software, and some implement it in mixed solidity and mixed of the L2 node software, responding to
软件，有些人以混合坚固性和L2节点软件的混合性实施
events that are coming out of the solidity. Both of these are valid strategies if you were to
来自坚固性的事件。如果您要
design one of these, or you're involved in designing these, you might want to consider
设计其中之一，或者您参与设计这些，您可能需要考虑
between both of them. And also, there's a mixed approach to how they deploy the addresses.
他们俩之间。而且，他们如何部署地址也有一种混合的方法。
Some of them use consecutive addresses. Arbitrum uses very low numbers. Optimism uses 4200,
其中一些使用连续的地址。仲裁使用非常低的数字。乐观使用4200，
bunch of zeros into theirs. And some systems use create-to-drivens. They'll just create the
一堆零进入他们的。有些系统使用创建对手。他们只会创建
contract, and when they deploy it, wherever the create-to-contract puts it at, or the create-to-one
合同，当他们部署它时，无论创建合同将其放在何处，
contract, that's what it is.
合同，就是这样。
They're going to use create2 because it has much more repeatable deployment semantics
他们将使用create2，因为它具有更重复的部署语义
based off the address.
基于地址。
But if you use consecutive addresses, you have the advantage of making the address obviously
但是，如果您使用连续的地址，则显然可以进行地址
a system contract, whereas when it's a create2-driven, you'd really have to know that that address
系统合同，而当它是由Create2驱动的时，您真的必须知道该地址
when you're working with it is the address you're working at when you look at it.
当您使用它时，当您查看它时正在工作的地址。
Because when you look at calling in the code an optimism address or an arbitrary address,
因为当您查看在代码中调用乐观地址或任意地址时
it's really obvious that there's no cryptographic key.
很明显，没有加密密钥。
The odds of it getting one that looks just as much like that.
它的几率看起来同样如此。
it's recognizable it's very low you know all all addresses are equally difficult to get but you're
可以识别它很低，您知道所有地址都很难获得，但是您是
predominantly going to get ones that are a mix of numbers all across so large sequences of zeros
主要将获得如此大的零序列的数字混合在一起
really hard to get so that's one advantage there another use of system contracts as i mentioned is
真的很难获得，这是我提到的另一个使用系统合同的优势
foreign host chain services um alt l once will use this to access their tokens um moonbeam aurora
外国主机连锁服务UM Alt L曾经将使用它来访问其令牌UM Moonbeam Aurora
hedera all have proxies to their alt l1 token systems um they have and they kind of make them
Hedera都有其Alt L1代币系统的代理
work within um the ethereum standards um so that people can come in with their defi stuff and do
在UM以太坊标准中工作，以便人们可以使用他们的fefi菜并做
defy things with them but still at the end of the day it's a polka dot or it's a near or it's
与他们抗衡，但归根结底，它是一个圆点，或者是一个圆点或
a hedera token um uh this is i think i didn't finish writing this slide completely some they
hedera doken嗯，这是我想我还没有完全写这片幻灯片
have access to account tools and systems that they might need to do on their different account models
可以访问他们可能需要在其不同的帐户模型上执行的帐户工具和系统
Moonbeam and Polkadot famously have voting and messaging across various all the one layers
Moonbeam和Polkadot在各种一层中都有投票和消息传递
that they could go to talk to other communications. And zk also exposes features zk sync has a
他们可以去与其他沟通交谈。 ZK还公开功能ZK Sync具有
class of storage it's immutable and they access this through through through pre compiles
储存类别是不变的，他们通过Pre Pre Compiles通过
Because they don't really have an opcode to access this.
因为他们实际上没有访问此操作的操作码。
Foreign host chain services.
外国主机连锁服务。
So when I'm talking about a foreign host chain, I'm talking about a blockchain that is not an EVM blockchain in its first day.
因此，当我谈论的是外国主机连锁店时，我说的是一个区块链，它在第一天就不是EVM区块链。
So if you take like Avalanche or Celo, those are basically EVM chains with customizations built onto it.
因此，如果您像雪崩或Celo一样，这些基本上是EVM链，并具有自定义的构建。
But if you were to take like a Cardano, a Solana, a Near, a Polkadot, those were built up without the EVM in mind.
但是，如果您要像Cardano一样，坐着溶剂，一个近距离，一个polkadot，那是在没有EVM的情况下建立的。
And they do their own things and they have their own decisions.
他们做自己的事情，并且有自己的决定。
So those are what I consider to be a foreign host.
因此，这些就是我认为是外国主持人。
And so what some of these chains have done, at least in the case of Polkadot and Near and Hedera,
因此，至少在Polkadot和附近的Hedera的情况下
is they brought in a system so that you can run EVM there and store their stuff on their chain and access it through EVM.
他们是否带入了一个系统，以便您可以在那里运行EVM并将其物品存储在链条上，并通过EVM访问它。
but that's not what they're intended, you know, what they were built on.
但这不是他们的意图，您知道它们的建立。
So you're taking one EVM system, you're going to a different EVM system.
因此，您正在使用一个EVM系统，您将进入另一个EVM系统。
It's kind of a foreign system. It's not the, it's like, you know,
这是一种外国系统。不是，就像，你知道，
having a Linux subsystem inside windows.
Windows内部具有Linux子系统。
When you call it some of the window stuff, it's a bit different.
当您称之为一些窗口的东西时，它会有所不同。
So that's kind of, you know, why I consider, you know,
所以，这是我知道的，为什么我会考虑，你知道，
a foreign host access is it basically got one operating system calling a
外国主机访问基本上是一个操作系统，
different operating system within the same process.
在同一过程中不同的操作系统。
And so there's, there's issues that come in there,
所以有，那里有问题，
which I think are on the next slide.
我认为下一个幻灯片。
Did it answer your question about what is meant by a foreign host chain?
它是否回答了您关于外国宿主连锁店意味着什么的问题？
And some of these foreign hosts, they have things,
其中一些外国主人有东西，
they were built on the premise of things that Ethereum wasn't building on.
它们建立在以太坊没有建立的事物的前提下。
Polkadot wanted to be like a layer zero that had communication across the chains.
Polkadot希望像一个零层的零层一样。
Cosmos is one that I missed out.
宇宙是我错过的。
They, you know, have this inner chain communication protocols.
您知道，他们拥有这种内部链条通信协议。
So they would have access to a lot of their systems through the precompile.
因此，他们可以通过预编译访问许多系统。
So you do things that were just not meant to be done in the EVF, and you access those through pre-compiles.
因此，您做的事情并不是要在EVF中完成的事情，并且可以通过预编译访问这些事情。
So one big thing to worry about when you do system calls is there is a security model that you need to be aware of.
因此，当您进行系统呼叫时，要担心的一件大事是您需要了解一个安全模型。
The biggest thing to note is that the pre-compiles don't share Ethereum's memory model.
要注意的最大的事情是，预编译没有共享以太坊的内存模型。
What do I mean by this?
我的意思是什么？
So in Ethereum, each contract has its own set of contract storage.
因此，在以太坊中，每个合同都有自己的合同存储组。
And only that contract can access it.
只有该合同才能访问它。
but you added another layer called a delegate call.
但是您添加了另一个称为委托呼叫的层。
And what that allows is for you as though another contract has your memory
允许的是给您，好像另一合同有您的记忆
model to act on your memory model as though it's you.
模型在您的内存模型上采取行动，就好像是您一样。
And that's the power of delegate calls.
这就是代表呼叫的力量。
And that's really how proxy contracts work is a proxy contract will deploy.
这确实就是代理合同的工作方式是代理合同将部署的。
It'll have memory there, but then a delegate calls out to other, other,
它会在那里有记忆，但随后委派召集其他，其他，
another contract that may just be very,
另一个可能非常非常的合同
it or versions of this where you fix bugs or add new features,
它或该版本的版本可以修复错误或添加新功能，
but the memory model stays the same.
但是内存模型保持不变。
So you'll call out to a contract that implements your V1 or your V2 or your V3.
因此，您将征求实现V1或V2或V3的合同。
You'll upgrade it.
您将升级它。
But the memory stays in the proxy contract.
但是记忆停留在代理合同中。
So with these delegate calls, you're not accessing the memory.
因此，使用这些委托呼叫，您将无法访问内存。
You have your own memory.
您有自己的记忆。
And also things like the sender address and the local address are maintained across these calls.
而且，在这些呼叫中，也可以维护诸如发送方地址和本地地址之类的东西。
Now, if you're not aware of that, what you might do is when you get a call coming into the system, you might say, well, who's calling me?
现在，如果您不知道这一点，您可能会做的是，当您接到系统中的电话时，您可能会说，谁在打电话给我？
And you might ask, you know, who's the sender and who's the address?
您可能会问，您知道，谁是发件人，谁是地址？
And you might do things as though it's them.
您可能会做一些事情，就好像是他们一样。
They have, you know, hackers are clever.
他们知道，黑客很聪明。
They found ways to abuse this through the delegate call.
他们找到了通过代表呼吁滥用这一滥用的方法。
And it's typically through other contracts that do callbacks.
而且通常是通过其他回电的合同。
And they'll, you know, they'll do a delegate call to something as a callback or the callback.
而且，他们会以回调或回调的方式进行代表呼吁。
They don't invoke the delegate call that it comes from the parent.
他们没有调用来自父母的代表呼叫。
And in short, what happens is they can impersonate people, make it look like someone that they're not.
简而言之，发生的事情是他们可以模仿人们，使它看起来像一个人。
And it's not perfect, but they can use techniques to what they've done.
这不是完美的，但是他们可以使用技术来实现自己的工作。
and this is pretty famous in um hedera had one we're not purely famous but hedera was hacked
这在Um Hedera中非常有名
by this and i'm not sure if moonbeam and near were if they just went through the um
这样，我不确定Moonbeam是否刚刚穿过UM
or if they went through the uh a security disclosure on this but they were able to drain
或者，如果他们对此进行了安全披露，但他们能够沥干
um uniswap style dexes of their liquidity into some of these contracts they deploy for contracts
UM UNISWAP风格的流动性将其用于合同的其中一些合同
for uh for callbacks um and because and the reason this has worked in these foreign chain
对于回调，嗯，因为这在这些外国链中起作用的原因
systems but not in EVM-based systems is because the memory model is different. Now, the solution
系统但在基于EVM的系统中不是是因为内存模型不同。现在，解决方案
to this is simple. It's to ban delegate call-ins to the system pre-compile. The way you do that
对此很简单。这是为了禁止在系统预编译的系统中呼叫。你这样做的方式
is you check that the address of the contract you deployed is the address of what you think it is.
您是否检查您部署的合同的地址是否是您认为的地址。
So when you deploy a contract in your constructor, you will save your address into your immutable
因此，当您在构造函数中部署合同时，您会将地址保存到不变的
data. In modern versions of Solidity, that's copied into the actual code that is deployed
数据。在现代版本的坚固性中，已复制到部署的实际代码中
with the contract, so that's an immutable feature of that code. So you can detect if you're being
有了合同，这是该代码的不变特征。因此您可以检测到您是否正在
called this delegate call or not, and you can say, no, I refuse to do that call. And when you control
打电话给这个代表是否致电，您可以说，不，我拒绝打电话。当你控制
the node software, you can do similar checks without having to burn in the address into it,
节点软件，您可以进行类似的检查，而无需在地址中燃烧，
but you can check and make sure if I'm being delegate called. And if you're being delegate
但是您可以检查并确保我是否被委派。如果你是代表
called, you can just refuse the system contract. And that's what Moonbeam does for their system
打电话，您可以拒绝系统合同。这就是Moonbeam为他们的系统所做的
contracts. That's what NIR does. And that's now what Hedera does to ensure that these aren't there.
合同。这就是尼尔所做的。现在，这就是Hedera为确保这些不存在的事情所做的。
Another issue, EVM chains, as far as pre-compiles, mostly those involve solidity bugs, and it's not really because of the system.
另一个问题是，就预编译而言，EVM链主要涉及坚固的错误，这并不是真正的原因。
Any hacks that have been involved in the EVM chains are not because of the EVM implementation per se, as much as it is the code.
EVM链中涉及的任何黑客都不是因为EVM实现本身，而不是代码。
What's notable about this, why I call this out, is because it exploits it.
为什么我称呼这一点值得注意的是因为它利用了它。
that there is a foreign chain underneath it, an EVM chain,
下面有一个外国链，一个EVM链，
trying to act like an EVM, but it's not quite an EVM.
试图像EVM一样行动，但这不是EVM。
And they were able to use the slight differences
他们能够使用略有差异
between the two to exploit it.
在两者之间利用它。
And so when you do these implementations,
因此，当您执行这些实现时，
you need to keep this in mind and make sure
您需要牢记这一点并确保
that any of the differences are blocked out.
任何差异都被阻止了。
The biggest thing it can do is band delegate calls.
它可以做的最大的事情是乐队代表呼叫。
But the next thing you need to be aware of
但是接下来您需要意识到
is the way reverts work.
是恢复工作的方式。
So someone might be able to call your system contract
因此有人可能会打电话给您的系统合同
and you might commit data.
您可能会提交数据。
And then later on it might be reverted.
然后后来可能会恢复。
If your wrap call is reverted, you need to make sure that your system contract changes are also reverted.
如果您的包装电话被恢复，则需要确保您的系统合同更改也会恢复。
I'm not sure, I'm not aware of any in the wild exploits of this yet,
我不确定，我还不知道这一点的任何东西，
because I think everyone who's been implementing this has been painfully aware of how reverts work
因为我认为正在实施此操作的每个人都痛苦地意识到如何恢复工作
and have built their systems so that any calls will be reverted,
并已经构建了他们的系统，以使任何呼叫都将被恢复，
if they're reverted within a scope will not have lingering side effects.
如果它们在范围内恢复，则不会产生挥之不去的副作用。
But this is, again, another thing when you build system contracts that you need to be aware of.
但这再次是您需要了解的系统合同时的另一件事。
and if it fully implements the EVM model,
如果它完全实现了EVM模型，
then you're fine.
那你很好。
But if it doesn't fully implement the EVM model,
但是，如果它没有完全实现EVM模型，
you need to take steps to ensure
您需要采取措施以确保
that if your system call gets reverted,
如果您的系统呼叫被恢复，
that the side effects don't linger.
副作用不会流连忘返。
And that's kind of the subtle genius
这是一种微妙的天才
of optimism solution to this,
对此的乐观解决方案，
where they write the stuff in Solidity,
他们在牢固地写东西的地方，
they emit events,
他们散发事件，
and then based on those emitted events,
然后根据那些发出的事件，
they do the actions in the L2 node.
他们在L2节点中执行操作。
Because the way the EVM works,
因为EVM的工作方式，
if you have to revert something,
如果您必须恢复某些内容，
all of the events get reverted too.
所有事件也被恢复。
um so it's it's kind of you know you keep it as simple as possible um it just subtly works great
嗯，所以您知道您将其保持尽可能简单，嗯，它巧妙地效果很好
so that's one of the one of the genius things about optimism why they've never had to worry
因此，这是关于乐观的天才之一，为什么他们永远不必担心
about this is because they use the evm as much as possible so one last thing i want to talk about
这是因为他们尽可能地使用EVM，所以我想谈的最后一件事
as far as the future of the evm apart from new contracts coming in
至于EVM的未来，除了新合同
is there's this notion of an idea called a progressive pre-compile um why is that not linked
有一个想法的想法，称为渐进的预编译嗯，为什么没有链接
Here we go.
开始了。
I'm using an old version of this.
我正在使用旧版本。
So before I get to progressive pre-compiles,
因此，在我进行进步的预编译之前，
I'm going to talk about some of the features of pre-compiles.
我将谈论预编译的一些功能。
Generally speaking on mainnet,
一般来说，关于主网，
there's resistance to adding new mainnet pre-compiles.
添加新的Mainnet预编译具有抵抗力。
The testing surface is high,
测试表面高，
and the problem is we have to carry them on forever.
问题是我们必须永远继续下去。
The experiences we had with Lake2 and with RipeMD
我们与Lake2和Ripemd的经历
make us hesitant to add things on there.
让我们犹豫要在那里添加东西。
We're going to have to maintain forever
我们将必须永远维护
all the chances someone might use it.
有人可能会使用它的所有机会。
So that's why BLS with it's nine separate functions,
这就是为什么BLS具有九个单独的功能，
it has been kind of a sticking point,
这是一个令人难以置信的点，
code's been ready since 2020 or 2021,
自2020年或2021年以来，代码已经准备就绪，
but it hasn't been implemented yet
但尚未实施
because the need hasn't been there,
因为需要
but because it's been implemented in the consensus layer
但是因为它是在共识层中实现的
and we need to verify these BLS signatures,
我们需要验证这些BLS签名，
that's why it's being brought in
这就是为什么它被带进来的原因
is there's a compelling need.
是否有令人信服的需求。
And it's a very high level of compelling need.
这是非常高的迫切需求。
That's the level of need that we would need
这就是我们需要的水平
to bring in a pre-compile into main net.
将预编译带入主要网络。
It's either essential to the feature or it's basically
它要么对功能必不可少，要么基本上是
it's got to be essential to some other feature it can't stand on its own so like one thing
它必须对其他功能至关重要，它不能独自站立
um that is working to solve some of this is there's a call called roll call it's all the
嗯，正在努力解决其中的一些是一个叫做“滚动呼叫的呼叫”
roll-ups the layer twos get together and they talk about some of their standards issues
卷起两者的两者聚在一起，他们谈论了一些标准问题
um and want to make sure that they're aligned on things that they should align on without you know
嗯，想确保他们在不知道的情况下应对的事情保持一致
having to make everyone work on the same item but one of the things that's falling out of this is
必须让每个人都在同一项目上工作，但是从中掉下来的一件事之一就是
their early collaboration is they're standardizing what the sccp-256-r1 pre-compile might look like
他们的早期合作是他们标准化SCCP-256-R1预编译的外观
and they're standardizing on an address,
他们正在标准化地址，
and they're standardizing on an interface
而且他们在界面上标准化
so that this exists across L2 precompiles.
因此，这是在L2预编译中存在的。
And the upside is if an L2 gets it wrong,
上行是如果L2弄错了，
it's only the L2 that has to live with it forever,
只有L2才能永远与之生活在一起，
not mainnet.
不是主网。
If one or two L2s implement it,
如果一个或两个L2实施它，
but if they get it right,
但是，如果他们做对了，
all the L2s will implement it,
所有L2S都将实施它，
and it will then come into mainnet
然后它将进入主网
because it's been proven.
因为它已被证明。
And this is some of the core developers
这是一些核心开发人员
on core Ethereum Layer 1,
在核心以太坊第1层上，
engineering efforts, they really want to go with this approach where things that
工程努力，他们真的想采用这种方法
might come into the EVM are first prototyped on layer two, and then when they're proven
可能会进入EVM首先是在第二层原型的，然后在证明它们时
successful and proven stable, then they come into layer one if layer one needs it.
成功且经过证实的稳定，然后如果第一层需要它，则将其进入第一层。
So this is an example, I think, of how the future pre-compiles coming into main net is going to
因此，我认为这是一个例子，说明未来的预编译如何进入主要网络
look, is we're going to be adopting, for the most part, layer two pre-compiles, or we're going to
看，我们将在大多数情况下采用第二层预编译，否则我们将要
be implementing layer one pre-compiles that are essential to features like Verkle or Blobs. And
实现对Verkle或Blob等功能必不可少的一层预编译。和
Blobs was the most recent one added, the KZG precompile,
斑点是最近添加的斑点，即KZG预编译，
because that was essential to it.
因为那对此至关重要。
One other thing that's probably going to be helping precompiles
另一件事可能会帮助预编译
is an EVM feature on the horizon called EVM Max.
是地平线上的EVM功能，称为EVM Max。
And the Max stands for Modular Math Extensions.
最大代表模块化数学扩展。
Modular...
模块化的...
I probably got that wrong.
我可能错了。
It was late at night when I wrote this.
当我写这篇文章时，已经很晚了。
But it's modular exponentiation.
但这是模块化的指数。
So it provides a lot of features to do modular math,
因此，它提供了许多进行模块化数学的功能，
modular add, modular divide,
模块化，模块化鸿沟，
that is essential to the way that the EC-DSA style curves work.
这对于EC-DSA样式曲线的工作方式至关重要。
And so aspirationally, their goal is to make sure that these things are within 2x the gas cost
因此，在志向上，他们的目标是确保这些东西在2倍之内
of what you might make a normal precompile costed with if you do it natively.
如果您本地进行工作，您可能会制作正常的预编译。
And because almost the entirety of the difficulty is handled in the modular math in these extensions,
而且由于这些扩展中的模块化数学中几乎所有难度都在处理，所以
it's very reasonable because moving bits around to move the answer around and pack it up,
这是非常合理的，因为四处走动以将答案移动并打包，
That's not terribly expensive.
那不是很昂贵。
The real expense comes in doing these 384-bit modular divisions of all the numbers that are very expensive to do in plain old EVM.
真正的费用是在所有数字中进行这384位模块化部门，这些数字在普通的旧EVM中非常昂贵。
So this also should reduce the need for precompiles because you can reasonably bring in your random curves.
因此，这也应该减少对预编译的需求，因为您可以合理地带入随机曲线。
You can reasonably bring in your random new features that are being done in elliptic curve type situations.
您可以在椭圆曲线类型的情况下合理地带入正在完成的随机新功能。
and you can do it specifically for what you need and you can optimize it.
您可以专门针对所需的工作，并且可以优化它。
And that's going to solve a lot of problems.
这将解决很多问题。
But that also opens up the next possibility, which is on the next arithmetic extension.
但这也打开了下一个可能性，这是下一个算术扩展。
Okay, modular arithmetic extension.
好的，模块化算术扩展。
Yeah, that's what it was for.
是的，就是这样。
But what's really coming up in the future is something called progressive pre-compiles.
但是，将来真正发生的事情就是渐进的预编译。
So this is a quasi-proposal.
因此，这是一个准能力。
Here's the link to the Ethereum magicians thread.
这是与以太坊魔术师线程的链接。
and uh the idea here is you write whatever you're going to do and you write it in evm
嗯，这里的想法是您写任何要做的事情，然后在EVM中写下它
and you nail it down you get it absolutely right you say this is the contract that we're going to
然后您将其钉住，您完全正确地说，您说这是我们要签的合同
do and so you would canonize that contract you would use techniques like create two to make
这样做，这样您就可以供您使用您使用的合同，例如创建两个技术来制作
sure it always gets proposed at the same address um and what you would do is your node software
当然，它总是在同一地址上提出，您将要做的是您的节点软件
would either use that evm code or they would implement it natively and get faster on it
要么使用该EVM代码，要么将其本地实施并更快地实施
So if we had EVM-Max out there and we had an EVM-Max version of SCCP-256-R1, or if we need to have R2 or any of the other different size curves, we need FIPS compliance, we need to implement some random curve out there, we would canonize it in EVM.
因此，如果我们有EVM-MAX，并且我们拥有SCCP-256-R1的EVM-MAX版本，或者我们需要具有R2或其他任何不同尺寸的曲线，我们需要FIPS合规性，我们需要实现一些随机曲线在那里，我们将在EVM中批量化。
So what's great about it is if you don't want to spend the time to write a native implementation, you just run the EVM version and you just get it for free.
因此，如果您不想花时间编写本机实现，那么您只需运行EVM版本，而您只需免费获得它即可。
You just bring the contract in.
您只需加入合同即可。
But if you need the speed, you can implement it locally and get the speed up.
但是，如果需要速度，则可以在本地实现并提高速度。
Now, one of the things that's an open question is how to handle gas.
现在，一个悬而未决的问题之一是如何处理汽油。
If you do it native, you're going to want to be able to charge less for it.
如果您这样做，那么您将希望能够为此收取少的钱。
But how we're going to signal that in the chains and how we're going to handle that
但是我们将如何在链条中表明这一点，以及我们将如何处理
has not been figured out.
尚未弄清楚。
And to really get this to work, we need to ship EVMX.
为了真正使它起作用，我们需要运送EVMX。
That's really, I think, it's going to unlock it.
我认为这确实会解锁它。
Now, one of the things that I think proves out this model that is viable
现在，我认为证明了这种可行的模型之一
is how clients have chosen to implement EIP-4788.
是客户选择实施EIP-4788的方式。
and this is where we're bringing the beacon block route
这就是我们带来的信标街区路线的地方
and we're putting it into the storage of smart contracts.
我们将其纳入智能合约的存储中。
Geth and Reth go simple.
Geth和Reth变得简单。
They just execute the contract.
他们只是执行合同。
And at the beginning of the block,
在街区开始时，
they create a transaction,
他们创建交易，
they point it at the contract
他们指出合同
and they just execute it.
他们只是执行它。
And the side effects are going to be fine.
而且副作用将很好。
They don't charge for gas.
他们不收费汽油。
They just let it run and do whatever it needs.
他们只是让它运行并尽其所能。
And they literally use the contract.
他们从字面上使用合同。
So it's a great example of how this works
因此，这是一个很好的例子
is that you might do,
是你可能会这样做
you know, that you can have the contract there.
您知道，您可以在那里签订合同。
Based with Nethermine though, they do it differently.
但是，它们的做法不同。
First, they look and see if the contract exists,
首先，他们查看并查看合同是否存在，
and if the contract exists,
如果合同存在，
then they just write the data directly to storage.
然后，他们只是将数据直接写入存储。
Go into the EVM layer,
进入EVM层，
they don't go to the execution,
他们不去执行，
they just do what the contract does and they have
他们只是做合同所做的事，他们有
the same side effects as though you implement it locally.
就像您在本地实施一样，相同的副作用。
I think this is an important proof of concept of
我认为这是重要的概念证明
how progressive pre-compiles might work
进步的预编译可能如何工作
and how they can exist in both worlds.
以及它们如何在两个世界中存在。
If your chain software wants to optimize it,
如果您的连锁软件想要优化它，
go ahead and optimize it as long as
继续进行优化，只要
all the side effects are the same.
所有副作用都是相同的。
And if you don't want to optimize it,
如果您不想优化它，
or you don't have time to optimize it,
或者您没有时间优化它，
just bring the EVM code in, and it works just the same.
只需将EVM代码带入其中，它也可以使用。
And I think this is, you know,
我认为这是
possibly how future pre-compiles might show up in the EVM.
可能未来的预编译可能会出现在EVM中。
We don't have to go through ACD.
我们不必经历ACD。
It's just going to be an implementation detail
这只是实现细节
that the clients will choose to implement.
客户将选择实施。
If there is a really, you know,
如果有的话，你知道，
like some 384 K2 curve that we need to support,
就像我们需要支持的384 k2曲线一样
I'm just making that up.
我只是在弥补。
I don't know if that's a real curve.
我不知道这是否是真正的曲线。
You know, you could write an EVM max
你知道，你可以写一个evm max
that would do all the math for you.
那将为您完成所有数学。
And if you don't have time to embed it, you just make sure it's on the chain, it gets executed.
而且，如果您没有时间嵌入它，则只需确保它在链上，它将被执行。
But if you really need to get the performance, you spend the time in the clients and you ship it as you're ready.
但是，如果您确实需要获得表演，则将时间花在客户身上，并在准备就绪时运送它。
You don't have to wait for a fork to implement this pre-compile and get the performance gains.
您不必等待叉子来实现此预编译并获得性能提高。
And that was actually kind of in the way original design approaches that they were going to handle smart contracts in Ethereum was that the gas costs on a contract, the more it executed, the cheaper it gets.
这实际上是一种原始设计方法的方式，他们将要处理以太坊的智能合约，就是合同中的汽油成本，越多，其执行越便宜。
The theory is it would incentivize the clients to implement some of these native contracts.
理论是它将激励客户实施其中一些本地合同。
That idea was ultimately pitched, but the core of it's kind of there, and that stuff that you need to go faster, you can just write faster, because the contract to the hash is fixed and immutable and never going to change.
这个想法最终被提出了，但是它的核心是您需要更快的东西，您可以更快地写作，因为与哈希的合同是固定的，不变的，永远不会改变。
So that's a quick summary of all of the things that are coming in the future, and not all of them, but some of the highlights of what I see in the future of pre-compiles.
因此，这是对未来所有事物的快速摘要，而不是全部，而是我将来在预编译中看到的一些亮点。
Great, so now I have time for any questions.
太好了，所以现在我有时间提出任何问题。
Let's go back to Rahul's.
让我们回到拉胡尔（Rahul）的。
Rahul asked earlier in the presentation,
拉胡尔（Rahul）在演讲早些时候问
if a bug gets reported in a pre-compile on a client or multiple,
如果在客户端或多个客户的预编译中报告错误，
what is the plan of action?
什么是行动计划？
Does it get patched in an update?
它在更新中得到修补吗？
Bugs have been found in pre-compiles before.
以前在预编译中发现了错误。
The core devs on main net,
主网上的核心开发人员
and I assume you're asking on main net,
我想您在主网上问
because if it's optimism or arbitrary,
因为如果是乐观或任意的，
I really can't speak for their process,
我真的不能说他们的过程，
but they have a much tighter team
但是他们的团队更加紧张
and they have a much tighter way to fix it.
他们有一种修复它的更严格的方法。
What's different for main net is you've got
主要网的不同之处在于您
at least four different teams, four to six teams,
至少四个不同的团队，四到六支球队，
that you need to communicate these changes to
您需要将这些更改传达给
and get the information to in a secure fashion
并以安全的方式获取信息
and get it shipped out.
并把它运出。
Now, if there's a bug in a pre-compile,
现在，如果预编译中有错误，
typically it's only gonna be one client
通常只会是一个客户
that's gonna have the bug.
那将有错误。
Maybe two if they're sharing a library, two or three,
如果他们共享两个或三个图书馆，也许有两个
but it's typically gonna be one or two bug,
但这通常是一个或两个错误，
one or two clients.
一个或两个客户。
We have a secure chat where we're all on it
我们有一个安全的聊天
and we talk about our bugs
我们谈论我们的错误
and we talk about what happened.
我们谈论发生了什么。
And from that information,
从这些信息，
we tend to look at our own software
我们倾向于看我们自己的软件
if it's just someone else has a bug
如果只是别人有一个错误
it makes sure we're not getting into the same issues
它确保我们不会陷入同样的​​问题
if we're not set up the same way.
如果我们没有以相同的方式设置。
And there's been a couple of times where I've, you know,
而且有几次我知道，我知道
someone said, we made this mistake because, you know,
有人说，我们犯了这个错误，因为，你知道，
this caused it happened.
这导致了它发生的。
I looked at our code it's like,
我看了我们的代码，就像
oh, we kind of do the same thing.
哦，我们也有同样的事情。
So we adopted their solution and vice versa.
因此，我们采用了他们的解决方案，反之亦然。
There's stuff that base is done that, you know,
有一些基础已经完成的事情，你知道，
we got burned on and it made other clients be more attentive
我们被烧毁了，这使其他客户更加专心
to some of the things that, that they would need to fix.
对于某些事情，他们需要修复。
So, and this is more than just pre-compile.
因此，这不仅仅是预编译。
We actually have it for all of EVM as well,
我们实际上也为EVM提供了它，
but there's, there's a,
但是有一个
there's a group where we'll talk about,
有一个我们将讨论的小组，
we'll disclose the bug.
我们将披露错误。
we'll ship a patch out, we'll ship a new version,
我们会发出一个补丁，我们将发货新版本，
and either within that version, if it's truly urgent
在该版本中，是否真的很紧急
and you need to, you know, wave the red flag,
而且您需要挥舞危险信号，
hey, you need to update it now,
嘿，您需要立即更新它，
you know, we'll give one of those patches out.
您知道，我们将提供其中一个补丁。
But if we don't know if any, if we found it ourselves
但是，如果我们不知道是否有，如果我们自己找到了
and we're fairly certain it's trying to exploit it,
而且我们可以肯定的是，它正在尝试利用它，
we'll ship it in a version, a version or a couple versions later,
我们将在版本，版本或几个版本中发货，
we'll announce, you know, the details of the bug.
您会宣布该错误的详细信息。
There's a number of bugs that this group has found
这个组发现了许多错误
that we haven't fully disclosed yet,
我们尚未完全披露，
even though they've been patched for months.
即使他们已经修补了几个月。
And, you know, there's no reason to give people ideas
而且，您知道，没有理由给人们的想法
is on necessarily where it'll look
在一定要看的地方
until we're sure that everything is sorted out.
直到我们确定一切都已经整理了。
But if it is, and then the wild bug,
但是，如果是，然后是狂野的虫子，
we will fix it as fast as possible.
我们将尽可能快地修复它。
I think Geth's last consensus break
我认为Geth的最后共识休息
had to do with them optimizing their,
与他们优化他们有关，
I think it was their copy,
我认为这是他们的副本，
when it pre-compiles,
当它预编译时，
across different versions had different side effects.
跨不同版本具有不同的副作用。
One of them was out of spec,
其中一个是不规格的，
and it was just like three or four years ago.
就像三，四年前一样。
But as far as bugs and pre-compiles,
但就错误和预编译而言，
it's been a while since we've had anything
自从我们有任何东西以来已经有一段时间了
it's been in main net.
它一直在主要网络。
Typically, we try and shake these out in test nets or dev
通常，我们尝试在测试网或开发人员中摇动这些
nets, and we get really aggressive and really crazy
网，我们变得非常积极，真的很疯狂
in the way we fuzz them and the things
以我们的方式融合他们和事物
we try and do to break them.
我们尽力打破它们。
OK, were there other questions?
好，还有其他问题吗？
Is there an EFU for new free compiles
有新免费编译的EFU吗
that are currently being considered?
目前正在考虑？
That's one worth discussing.
那是值得讨论的一个。
The current BLS EIP, I think, 257.
我认为当前的BLS EIP 257。
3527, is that the number?
3527，这是数字吗？
No, what was it?
不，这是什么？
Oh, here's four, yeah.
哦，这是四个，是的。
25, 37, pre-confile for BLS 12, 381.
25、37，BLS 12、381的预菲尔。
72, 12, that's actually a RIP, not an EIP.
72、12，这实际上是撕裂，而不是EIP。
So I'm going to EIP 25, 37 is the first one.
因此，我要去EIP 25，37是第一个。
This is bringing in the G1 and the G2 math,
这引入了G1和G2数学，
the three basic things that you need for BLS in the various groups.
在各组中，BLS所需的三个基本内容。
um then you have a pairing you need a map um mapping from g2 to g1 and fp and
嗯，您有一个配对，需要一个地图UM映射从G2到G1和FP，以及
bunch of moon math i don't understand i just know that it works and does the magic thing
一堆月亮数学，我不明白我只是知道它有效并做神奇的事情
so this is probably the biggest one this is one that's currently scheduled to go into prog
因此，这可能是最大的，这是目前计划进入Prog的最大一个
of all the ones in that list this is the one that's most likely to ship um the next one is 7212
在该列表中的所有列表中，这是最有可能发货的一个是7212
um will that show up here will it redirect us
嗯，在这里出现的意志会重定向我们
this is yeah actually this started out as an eip and it's going to become a rip
是的，实际上，这最初是EIP，它将成为RIP
because it's going to be shipped on the roll-up so it's got does it have the address yet
因为它将在卷起上运输，所以它已经有了地址
um p256 verify so this one is doing the r curve what's notable about the r curve
um p256验证，所以这是在R曲线上进行R曲线值得注意的
is this is used in consumer hardware.
这是在消费者硬件中使用的。
It's FIPS compatible.
FIP兼容。
So do I have my YubiKey?
那我有我的Yubikey吗？
But if you have those YubiKees,
但是，如果您有那些Yubikees，
those little things that you touch,
那些触摸的小东西，
those nubbies that you put into the side of your computer
您放入计算机侧面的那些nubbies
that touch the preview there,
那触摸那里的预览，
that have the hardware keys,
具有硬件密钥，
there's lots of consumer-grade keys for these.
这些都有很多消费级钥匙。
I think web, not web auth,
我认为Web，而不是Web auth，
the new web keys that Google and Facebook
Google和Facebook的新网络键
and GitHub are trying to push on you.
Github试图推动您。
The store the cryptographic keys on your phone,
商店手机上的密码键，
your computer system,
您的计算机系统，
so you don't have to manage your passwords.
因此，您不必管理密码。
Those use the R key.
这些使用R键。
And I've seen that there are some Rolex
我已经看到有劳力士
that have demo code
具有演示代码
of how they can use these validations
他们如何使用这些验证
to actually unlock account abstraction tasks.
实际解锁帐户抽象任务。
So you could have an AA account
所以您可以拥有一个AA帐户
that could be driven by an R key
可以由R键驱动
and that R key that could actually be
而那个键实际上可能是
on a consumer grade YubiKey type device
在消费级Yubikey类型设备上
that would hold that.
那会坚持。
um eip 7545 is another example of one that's going to be brought in um because of um another
um eip 7545是另一个示例，它将因um而被带入另一个例子
feature requires it that's going to be the vertical proof verification pre-compile we're
功能需要它是垂直证明验证预编译
probably going to bring that in in osaka as the current thinking um that'll give it room to change
可能会将其带入大阪，因为目前的思维嗯，它会给它带来改变的空间
if it needs to to support vertical if we bring it in prog that might lock us into things and
如果我们需要支持垂直方面，如果我们将其带入可能将我们锁定到事物中的prog中，并且
into vertical that might want to change so that's going to come in with a vertical in um osaka
进入可能需要更改的垂直方向，以便在大阪的垂直方向出现
most likely.
最有可能的。
And EIP-5988,
和EIP-5988，
that's the most controversial
那是最有争议的
of these four
这四个
that's being brought in,
那是被带进来的
but it's also another important one,
但这也是另一个重要的
and that's the Poseidon hash function.
这就是Poseidon哈希功能。
And that gets into some ZK stuff.
那陷入了一些ZK的东西。
ZK is really unhappy
ZK真的不开心
performance-wise
性能
when it's asked to do
当被要求这样做
a Kachak hash or a SHA hash.
kachak哈希或sha哈希。
Bit twiddling is not something
有点twiddling不是什么
that ZK-proof systems
那个防ZK的系统
are terribly good at.
非常擅长。
There's ways to do it,
有这样做的方法，
but it's kind of expensive.
但这很昂贵。
Poseidon is a hash function that is based off of elliptic curves. I don't know exactly how it works,
Poseidon是基于椭圆曲线的哈希函数。我不知道它是如何工作的，
but the big outside is that it can be implemented with the logic inside of a zk-proof
但是最大的外部是可以通过防zk-Prof的逻辑来实现它
much, much more efficiently, because the way it gets to its hash is much more friendly to the
更有效地，因为它到达哈希的方式对
way zk-systems work. They're using the same elliptic curve-like things to get the curves
ZK系统的工作方式。他们使用相同的椭圆曲线般的东西来获取曲线
done so yeah that answers care is yeah Poseidon hash is it's kind of a it uses elliptic curves
是的，答案护理是的，是的，Poseidon Hash是它使用椭圆曲线的
I don't think it does ecdsa per se but it is very very friendly to the way current zk systems work
我认为它本身不做ECDSA，但对当前ZK系统的工作方式非常友好
do imp do pre-compiles have any impact on network congestion
IMP确实会对网络充血有任何影响
not directly the only way they might have impact on network congestion is if you're passing a large
他们可能会对网络拥堵产生影响的唯一唯一的方法是，您是否经过一个大型
amount of data on the pre-compile and there's ready protocol hedges to keep that from having
关于预编译的数据量和有现成的协议对冲，以防止它
too much of an impact um famously geth won't gossip any transaction over 128k um it there's
Geth不会在128K超过128k的任何交易中闻名的太多影响
ways to get stuff larger than that but it's it's kind of a pain in the neck so the transaction size
使东西更大的方法，但这是脖子上的疼痛，所以交易大小
limits are there there's also gas costing that we're charging on the um on the payload of a
限制还有天气成本，我们正在为UM收取有效载荷的费用
transaction bringing large amounts of data so as far as having a large pre-compile call that
交易带来了大量数据
that wouldn't necessarily cause any network congestion.
这不一定会引起任何网络拥塞。
That's really where the network would be hit.
这确实是网络被打击的地方。
It doesn't, you know, it's, there's better ways
您知道，这不是更好的方法
to cause network congestion problems
引起网络拥塞问题
than by abusing pre-compiles.
而不是滥用预编译。
Abusing pre-compiles are how you would
滥用预编译是您的方式
cause execution slowdowns.
导致执行放缓。
And we put a lot of effort into making sure
我们付出了很多努力来确保
that any ways that you could abuse it
您可以滥用它的任何方法
are less efficient than just doing a bunch of chat calls.
效率较小，而不是进行一堆聊天电话。
That's probably, or that's the hardest thing to optimize
可能是，或者那是最难优化的事情
because it's already a very optimized operation.
因为它已经是一个非常优化的操作。
So as long as anything that we can do
只要我们能做的任何事情
is more efficient than a chat call,
比聊天电话更有效，
then it's it's solved a lot of our problems.
然后，它解决了很多问题。
Is that it for the pre-compile questions?
是为了编译前问题吗？
Okay, I addressed the one about Java code and Bayesu.
好吧，我向有关Java代码和贝叶的一个讲话。
cool um any other questions
冷却其他任何问题
okay thank you so much um yeah uh regarding pretty miles maybe i wanted to ask if you can
好的，非常感谢你嗯，嗯，嗯，也许我想问你是否可以
elaborate a bit what are the what are the issues with adding a pre-compile uh you we have these
详细说明添加预编译的问题是什么，您有这些
proposals you you went went over uh so yeah what are the other challenges that you see like for
您去了您的建议，是的，您看到的其他挑战是什么
for example, but you meant, but we'll say then,
例如，但是您的意思是，但是我们会说，
but I hear the problem is that it would enshrine only like one set of
但是我听说问题是它只会像一组一样
parameters for the hash, which is not used by other chains and so on.
哈希的参数，其他链没有使用，依此类推。
So yeah, what are, what are the challenges? I think,
是的，有什么挑战？我认为，
I think these pre-compiles, what is the complexity?
我认为这些预编译，复杂性是什么？
Right. So, I mean, we can kind of see that in ECDSA.
正确的。因此，我的意思是，我们可以在ECDSA中看到这一点。
We don't have an ECDSA pre-compile.
我们没有ECDSA预编译。
That was the original pitch of 2537 of the BLS.
那是BLS 2537的原始音调。
And the first implementation was to bring in the BLS things.
第一个实施是引入BLS。
Writing a very generic hash function that could be parameterized, it has a huge test surface as far as performance.
编写一个非常通用的哈希函数，可以被参数化，它的测试表面就具有巨大的性能。
And the experience we had with ModDXP, we're kind of shy to bringing in things with huge unknown and unscalable performance issues.
我们在MODDXP上的经验，我们很害羞地引入巨大的未知和不可估量的性能问题。
It's just a great opportunity to cause security issues.
这只是引起安全问题的绝佳机会。
So that's why when we bring in specific pre-compiles, we would like specific curves.
因此，这就是为什么当我们引入特定的预编译时，我们会想要特定的曲线。
And this is why I'm very bullish on the progressive pre-compile and EVM-Max,
这就是为什么我非常看好渐进的预编译和EVM-MAX的原因，
because it seems like Poseidon could be implemented using EVM-Max.
因为似乎可以使用EVM-MAX实施Poseidon。
And you could have a contract that implements my curves parameters,
您可以拥有一份实现我的曲线参数的合同，
or you could have a contract that implements your curves parameters,
或者您可以拥有实现曲线参数的合同，
and you can bring those in on equal terms.
您可以同等地将它们带入。
So that is, you know, one of the concerns with bringing in Poseidon is, you know,
因此，您知道，引进波塞冬的问题之一就是
what parameters do we bring in?
我们带来什么参数？
is everyone okay with those parameters and does that suit your particular zk system is that going
每个人都可以使用这些参数，并且确实适合您的特定ZK系统
to be something that's going to work for you or is it going to be you know do you need the 257
要成为对您有用的东西，还是会成为您知道257
byte version the 200 i don't know what these parameters are but these are the types of things
字节版本200我不知道这些参数是什么，但是这些是事物的类型
that when i look into the various uh um cryptographic things there's just all sorts
当我研究各种uh um加密事物时，就会有各种各样的
of little little knobs and things you can tweak that the cryptographers um know exactly why they
小旋钮和可以调整的东西，密码学家嗯，确切知道他们为什么
need it and they know exactly why they need that number um so and they're they're really you know
需要它，他们确切地知道为什么他们需要那个数字，所以他们是他们真的知道
They really want to have what exactly they need in there for high-performance reasons.
他们真的希望出于高性能原因而拥有他们确切需要的东西。
But we can't, when we do a precompile,
但是我们不能，当我们进行预编译时，
have a huge open system that is difficult to test the surface of
具有巨大的开放系统，难以测试
because that's going to put significant risks in main net.
因为这将在主要网络中带来重大风险。
Now, if you want to try that on L2, nothing's stopping you
现在，如果您想在L2上尝试一下，什么都没有阻止您
because only the L2 will be at fault if things go really –
因为如果事情真的发生，只有L2才会有错 -
fault's probably not the right word, but only L2 will be at risk.
故障可能不是正确的词，但只有L2会处于危险之中。
If there is a bug in the precompile,
如果预编译中有错误，
it's going to be a lot easier within an L2.
在L2内会容易得多。
to fix that and bring it in right now
解决这个问题并立即将其带入
because they all have that security council.
因为他们都有安全委员会。
Even in no training wheels mode,
即使没有训练轮模式，
there's like an opportunity to bring in,
有一个机会，
you know, these keys to shut everything down.
您知道，这些关键要关闭所有内容。
Can't do that on main net.
无法在主要网上这样做。
If something bad gets shipped on main net,
如果主要网上发货的东西，
it's going to be there forever.
它将永远存在。
So that's, I think, where a lot of the hesitancy
我认为这是很多犹豫的地方
to bring in pre-compiles comes in
引入预编译
is that a lot of these are a one-way door.
这是其中很多是单向门。
And if we get it wrong,
如果我们错了，
picking up the pieces from a broken pre-compile
从破碎的预编译中捡起碎片
is going to be very difficult.
将非常困难。
Right, so is there, was there ever any discussion about removing pre-compiles?
是的，那么，是否有关于删除预编译的讨论？
Like for example, the identity that you mentioned in the beginning, which is like the ineffective
例如，您在开头提到的身份，就像无效
memory copy, yeah?
记忆副本，是吗？
Yeah, there is discussion of removing pre-compiles.
是的，有关于删除预编译的讨论。
The big reason is it would simplify client software.
最大的原因是它将简化客户端软件。
I think the three ones most at risk of being removed are, like you mentioned, the identity,
我认为，就像您提到的身份一样
the WRIP MD, and the Blake function.
wrip MD和Blake功能。
And those are based on one of the justifications is that they have low it's almost zero uses.
这些是基于理由之一的是，它们的用途几乎为零。
And in some stretches of blocks, they do have zero uses.
在某些块中，它们的用途确实为零。
So there's been talk of removing these, but I think what's more likely going to happen
因此，有关于将其删除的话题，但我认为更有可能发生的事情
instead of removing them is they might instead migrate to a contract.
而不是删除它们，而是他们可能会迁移到合同中。
If we could do ripe MD in a reasonably sized EVM contract, I could see us migrating that
如果我们可以在合理尺寸的EVM合同中做成熟的MD，我可以看到我们正在迁移
to a fixed contract that you would then execute and gas prices would appropriately go up.
固定合同，您将执行该合同，而汽油价格将适当上升。
The same thing with the Blake function,
Blake功能的同一件事，
migrate it to a contract that the prices
将其迁移到价格的合同
would then appropriately go up.
然后会适当上升。
Identity, there's actually bytecode out there that does it,
身份，实际上有字体模式可以做到这一点，
you know, gas prices go up on it.
您知道，汽油价格上涨。
But I mean, when it comes to stuff like some of these,
但是我的意思是，当涉及到其中的一些事情时
like some of these things,
像其中一些事情一样
you just don't use them in new operations.
您只是不在新操作中使用它们。
And unless you're doing auditor,
除非您正在做审核员，否则
un-recommended things with your calls,
您的电话未征用的事情，
if you're doing like gas limited calls
如果您像汽油有限的电话一样
or relying on certain stipend returns for the calls,
或依靠某些电话的津贴回报，
then rising the prices are on some of these pre-compiles,
然后上涨的价格是这些预编译中的一些，
the solution is send in more gas.
解决方案是发送更多气体。
So the downsides of those, isn't that bad.
因此，这些缺点并不糟糕。
And what it does is it moves the logic
它的作用是移动逻辑
out of the client code, moves it into the EVM,
在客户端代码中，将其移至EVM中，
and it, you know, it solves a lot of problems.
您知道，它解决了很多问题。
It's just, it's just another EVM program.
只是，这只是另一个EVM程序。
Okay, awesome.
好吧，很棒。
Yeah, thank you so much, Dana.
是的，非常感谢，达娜。
I have one question unrelated to pre-compiles
我有一个与预编译无关的问题
more about like Bessu and Java,
更多关于Bessu和Java的更多信息，
because I often read that there are new Java versions,
因为我经常读到有新的Java版本，所以
like, you know, I can use the Java 23, 21,
就像，你知道，我可以使用Java 23，21，
right now, I believe.
我相信现在。
So I'm wondering, like, what version Bessu uses
所以我想知道，贝苏用了什么版本
and what are challenges in updating to new versions
更新到新版本时面临哪些挑战
and what are potential benefits?
什么是潜在的好处？
So, yeah, so there's, Java's interesting in that
所以，是的，所以有，爪哇很有趣
it's a system that runs, you run your programs in,
这是一个运行的系统，您可以运行程序，
and you can upgrade the Java system underneath it
您可以升级下面的Java系统
almost always without problem.
几乎总是没有问题。
They do a lot of backwards compatibility.
他们做了很多向后的兼容性。
So right now, BASU compiles with Java 17.
因此，现在，Basu用Java 17编译。
The code has to be in Java 17.
该代码必须在Java 17中。
And when we build it on the build server,
当我们在构建服务器上构建时，
Justin has it set up as a GitHub action.
贾斯汀将其设置为GitHub动作。
It uses the Java 17 compiler,
它使用Java 17编译器，
and it compiles it to Java 17.
它将其编译到Java 17。
But from that bytecode,
但是从该字节码，
you can change the system underneath it to run Java 21.
您可以将其下面的系统更改为运行Java 21。
And just by changing from Java 17 to Java 21,
只是从Java 17更改为Java 21
you get like a 20% speed increase.
您会增加20％的速度。
It's amazing the sum of the stuff
很棒的东西的总和
that they've done with JIT technology.
他们已经完成了JIT技术。
It's crazy stuff.
这是疯狂的东西。
So the problem is coming in upgrading.
因此，问题正在升级。
So we want to go from Java 17 to Java 21.
因此，我们想从Java 17到Java 21。
That's something that's going to happen in basically within the next year,
这是明年基本上会发生的事情，
maybe a number of months. It's hard to tell.
也许几个月。很难说。
But we need to make sure that all of our, our tools support Java 21.
但是我们需要确保我们所有的工具都支持Java 21。
Gradle is famous for, for lagging in their support.
格拉尔以落后的支持而闻名。
They're always about six months behind. You know,
他们总是落后大约六个月。你知道，
they don't support the most recent one I was getting always got to wait for a
他们不支持我一直在等待的最新一个
little bit. So our build tooling needs to support it.
一点。因此，我们的构建工具需要支持它。
And then some of our libraries that we use need to support it.
然后我们使用的一些库来支持它。
One that's currently about to be fixed,
一个目前即将修复的
web3j had some incompatibilities
Web3J有一些不兼容
with the newer version of Gradle.
带有较新版本的Gradle。
So we had to use an older version of Gradle
所以我们必须使用较旧版本的gradle
that didn't support 21.
不支持21。
This is mostly, you know, just, you know,
这主要是，您知道，只是，您知道
good old build engineering, software engineering issues.
良好的旧构建工程，软件工程问题。
When you want to upgrade a version,
当您想升级版本时，
it's you got to make sure the entire tangle
您必须确保整个纠结
of dependencies you have can support Java 21.
您拥有的依赖项可以支持Java 21。
A lot of the tools we're using, we're using tools that are,
我们使用的许多工具，我们都使用的工具
you know, we try to stay away from tools that are,
你知道，我们试图远离工具
have become ossified and never changed.
已经变得僵化，从未改变。
So we tend to remove those when we find those.
因此，当我们找到这些时，我们倾向于将其删除。
GCOCO, which is a build tool we use
GCOCO，这是我们使用的构建工具
to judge coverage on our tests,
判断我们的测试的覆盖范围，
they're pretty good about keeping that up to date.
他们对保持最新状态非常好。
So that's another one we upgrade Gradle.
这是我们升级Gradle的另一个。
So upgrading it to Java 21 is something
因此，将其升级到Java 21是什么
that's gonna be happening here in the short term.
这将在短期内发生。
Now, Java is kind of an interesting beast.
现在，爪哇是一种有趣的野兽。
Not every release is supported for long-term.
并非每个释放都得到长期的支持。
The pattern that they have decided to adopt is like every four releases is what's called a long-term release.
他们决定采用的模式就像每四个发行版一样，就是长期发布。
So there's newer versions of Java 17 being supported, but Java 18, 19, and 20, those versions have had their last release for the most part.
因此，支持Java 17的较新版本，但是Java 18、19和20，这些版本在大多数情况下都具有最后版本。
Java 21 is another one of those versions that will get more repeated support.
Java 21是将获得更多重复支持的另一个版本。
So Java 21 will be supported for a number of years.
因此，Java 21将得到多年的支持。
So a lot of projects, what they do, what Base has been doing for a while, is we will target one of the long-term support releases, either the current or the previous one.
因此，许多项目，他们的工作，一段时间以来一直在做什么，我们将针对当前或上一个的长期支持发布之一。
And while we're on the previous one, we'll migrate to the current one.
当我们使用前一个时，我们将迁移到当前的迁移。
So before that was Java 11.
所以在那之前是Java 11。
And so we did a migration from Java 11 to Java 17 a couple years ago.
因此，几年前，我们从Java 11迁移到Java 17。
And it's been a couple years.
已经有几年了。
And now we're going to do one from Java 17 to 21.
现在，我们将从Java 17到21做一个。
In a couple years, we'll go to Java 21 and 25.
几年后，我们将前往Java 21和25。
And what's exciting about upgrading to new versions of Java, which is something you don't really see in Solidity that much, but you get to use new language features and new things that just generally make things faster.
升级到新版本的Java的令人兴奋的是，这是您真正牢固地看到的东西，但是您可以使用新的语言功能和新事物通常使事情更快。
Like, we have this library called immutables, but there's a new feature called records in Java 17 that we can use to replace it.
就像，我们有这个名为Immutables的库，但是Java 17中有一个名为Records的新功能，我们可以用来替换它。
In Java 21, there is a new binary access layer to native libraries that shouldn't be much easier for us to bring in arbitrary libraries by using Java 21.
在Java 21中，有一个新的二进制访问层对本机库，对于我们而言，使用Java 21来引入任意库应该不那么容易。
it's not there in Java 17.
在Java 17中不存在。
So it just unlocks new features.
因此，它只是解锁了新功能。
And this, you know, this is,
这是，这就是
when people talk about ossifying EVM,
当人们谈论骨化EVM时，
you know, Java's been doing virtual machines
你知道，爪哇一直在做虚拟机
since the 20th century.
自20世纪以来。
EVM is another virtual machine.
EVM是另一台虚拟机。
I like to try and apply some of the lessons
我喜欢尝试应用一些课程
and some of the best practices learned
还有一些最佳实践
and avoid some of the worst practices.
并避免一些最糟糕的做法。
You know, we've seen mistakes made in Java.
你知道，我们已经看到爪哇犯了错误。
So we've mostly avoided some of those in the EVM.
因此，我们主要避免了EVM中的一些。
But it adopts some of those best practices in EVM.
但是它在EVM中采用了其中一些最佳实践。
One of those, we don't have time to dig into this in this talk,
其中之一，我们没有时间在这次演讲中进行研究，
one of those that I feel passionately about is the EVM object format.
我热衷于EVM对象格式之一。
And that does a simple change, which is takes the EVM code,
这会做一个简单的更改，这是获得EVM代码的，
writes a container format for it,
为其写一个容器格式，
does the minimal amount of change to support that container format.
为了支持该容器格式的最小变化是否最小。
And that gives us ways so that Layer 2s can compatibly experiment in EVM,
这为我们提供了方式，因此第2层可以在EVM中兼容实验，
signal that they're experimenting, and do exciting things.
表明他们正在实验，并做令人兴奋的事情。
And it basically keeps the core EVM the same, it just puts a package around it.
它基本上使核心EVM保持不变，它只是在其周围放置一个包装。
And that's what the JVM has done with its class format.
这就是JVM使用其班级格式所做的。
It's always had a container for its class format.
它总是有一个用于班级格式的容器。
And it puts signals in its class file that says, hey, I was compiled with Java 7.
它在其类文件中放置了信号，上面写着，嘿，我被Java 7编译了。
Can you support me?
你能支持我吗？
I was compiled with Java 8.
我被Java 8编译了。
And literally it's been written, there's code that has been written all the way back in Java 1.0 and in the betas that still runs and executes in the JVM.
从字面上看，它已经编写了，有代码一直在Java 1.0中一直编写，并且在JVM中仍在运行和执行的Beta中。
Because the execution sees that and it executes it.
因为执行会看到它并执行它。
Now, some of the things that gets us in trouble, and why I don't necessarily want to do that in the EVM to support just as big, thick history as Java does, is some things are forever.
现在，有些使我们陷入困境的事情，以及为什么我不一定想在EVM中这样做以像Java一样大，厚实的历史，这是有些事情永远的。
There's code in there that they just can't get rid of.
那里有代码无法摆脱。
So it's not always, you know, we can't just, you know, do a new version every time you do a hard fork.
因此，您知道，每次您执行艰苦的分叉时，我们都不总是能做一个新版本。
That's not necessarily a viable container version thing.
这不一定是可行的容器版本。
But that also, they've introduced some things that are much more complex than needed.
但这也是他们介绍了一些比所需的要复杂得多的事情。
The complexity in some of the Java stuff, I think, is a testament to why keeping things simple in EVM is important.
我认为，某些Java东西的复杂性证明了为什么保持EVM中的事情很重要。
Because, you know, there used to be this saying that, oh, Macs never get viruses.
因为，您知道，曾经有这样的说法，哦​​，Mac永远不会感染病毒。
They never get Trojans.
他们永远不会得到特洛伊木马。
There was a bug in some of the it was it violated the spec of the Java VM.
其中一些错误违反了Java VM的规格。
But the Java implementation, you could do some things to confuse the type checking on there.
但是Java实现，您可以做一些事情来混淆那里的类型检查。
And you could escape and you could do things to escape the sandbox.
您可以逃脱，您可以做一些事情来逃脱沙箱。
And so from a Java applet at the time systems were configured to just install and run, you could install a Trojan on your system.
因此，从Java Applet中，系统系统配置为仅安装和运行，您可以在系统上安装特洛伊木马。
People, their Macs would get owned because they're running Java applets.
人们，他们的Mac会因为正在运行Java小程序而获得所有。
You'll notice that Java applets don't exist anymore. Flash doesn't exist anymore.
您会注意到Java小程序不再存在。 Flash不再存在。
As a category, those sorts of things that can do system level things have been expunged from most systems.
作为一个类别，可以从大多数系统中删除了可以完成系统级别的事情。
So that's why, you know, my talk in system contracts is very limited in what you do.
因此，这就是为什么我在系统合同中的演讲非常有限。
and you need to be careful of the security
而且您需要小心安全性
because there's things that have been violated
因为有侵犯的东西
because of that.
因此。
Thank you so much for that.
非常感谢您。
It's very interesting from your OG senior Java perspective
从您的OG高级Java角度来看，这非常有趣
and the bridge to the EVM, the LTS releases.
和通往EVM的桥，LTS发布。
It's very interesting.
这很有趣。
Thank you so much.
太感谢了。
We have one more question here before we wrap up from Discord.
在总结不和谐之前，我们在这里还有一个问题。
What's the process of defending Gasco?
捍卫加斯科的过程是什么？
for pre-compile.
用于预编译。
So you mentioned that you always counter
所以你提到你总是对抗
the worst-case scenario for pricing the compile.
定价编译的最坏情况。
How do we even arrive at this gas price?
我们甚至如何达到这个气价？
That's an excellent question.
这是一个很好的问题。
And it's changed over the years.
这些年来发生了变化。
But ultimately, you come up with a few implementations
但最终，您想出了一些实现
on the various clients.
在各种客户上。
You make sure the clients implement it.
您确保客户实施它。
And you'll have one client that will be the lead,
而且您将有一个客户将成为领导者，
and they'll get their estimations on the gas.
他们将获得对天然气的估计。
But what you'll do is you'll get all of the typical
但是您要做的就是将获得所有典型的
and worst-case usages,
和最坏的用法，
and you'll get them in a tight loop.
而且您将使它们紧密地循环。
And you'll figure out how much benchmark,
您会弄清楚多少基准，
you know, wall clock time it takes
你知道，壁钟时间
to execute these compilers, these pre-compiles.
要执行这些编译器，这些预编译。
So you'll figure out what the real actual
因此，您将弄清楚实际的实际
wall clock time of these to execute is.
这些执行的壁时钟时间是。
And you might compare it with a benchmark on a system
您可以将其与系统上的基准进行比较
to give, like, a comparison.
进行比较。
But I think one of the more effective ways
但是我认为最有效的方法之一
it's happened, and this was for the,
发生了，这是为了
Mod EXP, when they were rationalizing their prices, they just picked a mega gas per second
mod exp，当他们合理化价格时，他们只是每秒挑选一个巨型汽油
standard that it should execute out of the air. I think at the time it was 30 or 35,
标准它应该在空中执行。我认为当时是30或35岁，
maybe it was 25. The number's gone up over the years. I think 25 was the initial goal.
也许是25岁。多年来，这个数字增加了。我认为25是最初的目标。
I think the BLSs were calculated against 35 mega gas as the goal. So if you take this pre-compile,
我认为BLS是针对35个Mega Gas作为目标进行计算的。因此，如果您进行此预编译，
you execute it in a tight loop, you give it the worst possible answers, it's going to burn about
您以紧密的循环执行它，给它一个最糟糕的答案，它将燃烧
35 million gas per second on it. So the premise being that the worst thing you can do with it
每秒3500万天气。因此，前提是您能做的最糟糕的事情
is to do that. And the goal is to make it so that Kachak has the worst solution for that.
就是这样做。目的是实现这一目标，以便Kachak拥有最糟糕的解决方案。
So, I mean, if we're going to, we're talking about repricing BLS based off of the old numbers,
因此，我的意思是，如果我们要这样做，我们正在谈论基于旧数字的重新定位BLS，
because everyone's performance on their VMs has gone up since then. So we're probably going to
因为从那以后，每个人在VM上的表现都在上升。所以我们可能会去
look at a new number, I don't know if it's going to be 40 or 60 or 80 megagas. But it means that
看看一个新的数字，我不知道它是否将是40或60或80兆瓦。但这意味着
The cost of the precompile is going to necessarily go up, unfortunately.
不幸的是，预编译的成本必然会增加。
But the goal there is to make sure that if they use it as a denial-of-service attack,
但是，目的是确保如果他们将其用作拒绝服务的攻击，
that it is not the most efficient way to cause a denial-of-service attack in Ethereum.
这不是在以太坊引起拒绝服务攻击的最有效方法。
It's going to cost you money in gas, and there's going to be more efficient operations to cause it to slow down.
它将花费您的天然气钱，并且将会有更有效的操作使其放慢速度。
And I know there's been a lot of talk on base that they have this dream of being gigagas,
而且我知道基地有很多谈话，他们有一个成为gigagas的梦想，
and this is going to be one of the tough battles
这将是激烈的战斗之一
is to figure out how to deal with pre-compiles.
是要弄清楚如何处理预编译。
But I think the battle to gigagas
但是我认为与吉加斯的战斗
is going to be conquered with tools like concurrency
将被诸如并发之类的工具征服
to solve it, not more than just parallelization.
要解决它，而不仅仅是并行化。
I think there's a lot of concurrency ideas
我认为有很多并发想法
that need to be brought in
需要带进来
that are well-known in the operating systems
在操作系统中众所周知
that we just need to bring into the EVM
我们只需要带入EVM
to construct our chain
建造我们的链
so that we can execute in a concurrent fashion
这样我们就可以以并发的方式执行
the blocks and build the blocks concurrently
块并同时构建块
So that we can get that giga gas number on because none of the pre compiles execute on a giga gas level. They're all, they all have various you know some of them have like you know hundreds of mega gas, and some of them aren't so that's going to be like one of the barriers to hit reliable giga gas.
这样我们就可以在Giga气体数量上获得，因为没有一个Pre汇编在Giga气体水平上执行。他们全部，他们都有各种各样的您知道其中一些人所知道的，就像您知道的数百种巨型汽油一样，其中有些人并不是这样，这就像击中可靠的Giga Gas的障碍之一一样。
That's very interesting.
那很有趣。
Thank you so much, Dano.
非常感谢，达诺。
I haven't realized that there might be even a problem with pricing for, I mean, huge problem
我没有意识到价格可能有问题，我的意思是，巨大的问题
even have performant enough client to be able to handle those giga gas numbers, but it's
甚至有足够的客户能够处理这些Giga气体号码，但这是
very interesting insight.
非常有趣的见解。
Yeah, thanks so much.
是的，非常感谢。
Yeah, we are out of time.
是的，我们没有时间。
I think we can wrap up here.
我认为我们可以在这里总结。
But it was really great.
但这真的很棒。
Thank you so much, Dano.
非常感谢，达诺。
Appreciate it so much.
非常感谢。
learned a lot today for sure and it's been it's been it's been a great great journey
今天肯定学到了很多东西，那一直是一个很棒的旅程
thank you so much for joining us today great thanks awesome thanks thanks dano and for
非常感谢您今天加入我们的加入，非常感谢，谢谢Dano和
everyone watching we'll see you on wednesday for our final research track session with francesco
每个人都在观看，我们将在周三见到您，参加我们与Francesco的最后一项研究曲目
on some consensus upgrades.
在一些共识升级上。
Thanks, everyone.
谢谢大家。
Thanks so much. Have a great day.
非常感谢。祝你有美好的一天。